<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="https://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="https://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Mary McCoy &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<atom:link href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/category/mary/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/</link>
	<description>Los Angeles De-Mythified</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 19:42:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-1947logoSquare-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>Mary McCoy &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>A Second Chance</title>
		<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/03/19/a-second-chance/</link>
					<comments>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/03/19/a-second-chance/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2008 18:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[attempted murder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[attempted suicide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Domestic Violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[long beach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>March 19, 1927 Long Beach, CA Fred and Lela McElrath had been married for 25 years, and raised three children together, now grown. But just as the couple should have been settling down into contented empty nesthood, a violent disagreement nearly destroyed it all. Fred wanted to leave Long Beach for Freewater, Oregon, where they&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/03/19/a-second-chance/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">A Second Chance</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/03/19/a-second-chance/">A Second Chance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>March 19, 1927<br />
Long Beach, CA</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="//farm4.static.flickr.com/3103/2345049446_6a45978606_m.jpg" alt="longbeachshooting" width="240" height="217" align="left" />Fred and Lela McElrath had been married for 25 years, and raised three children together, now grown.  But just as the couple should have been settling down into contented empty nesthood, a violent disagreement nearly destroyed it all.</p>
<p>Fred wanted to leave Long Beach for Freewater, Oregon, where they owned a ranch; however, Lela was determined to stay put.  She moved out of their home at <a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=45+atlantic+avenue,+los+angeles,+ca&amp;sll=37.0625,-95.677068&amp;sspn=29.219963,59.765625&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=33.769462,-118.185081&amp;spn=0.007474,0.014591&amp;z=16" target="_blank" title="atlantic">45 Atlantic Avenue</a>, and Fred spent nearly a week trying to track her down.  On March 18, they finally agreed to meet at a neutral location, their daughter&#8217;s home at 32 Neptune Place, and try to talk things through.</p>
<p>However, Lela refused to reconsider, and walked away from the argument.  As she was descending the stairs in her daughter&#8217;s house, Fred pulled out a gun and shot her twice in the back before turning the gun on himself, firing into his mouth.  The shots didn&#8217;t kill Lena, and when she was admitted to Seaside Hospital, it was assumed that she would recover.  However, Fred was barely clinging to life, and in fact, police arriving on the scene initially believed him dead.</p>
<p>Today, things looked drastically different.  A bullet was lodged behind Fred&#8217;s left ear, but doctors expected that he would make a full recovery &#8212; and in all likelihood, be left to stand trial for his wife&#8217;s murder.  The shots fired into his wife&#8217;s back had punctured her right lung, and she was not expected to live.  Authorities stood watch at Fred&#8217;s bed, waiting to charge him either with murder or attempted murder.</p>
<p>Shockingly, the story has a moderately happy ending.  On April 11, a frail Lena McElrath, appeared at her husband&#8217;s preliminary hearing and was helped to the stand by her son, where she made an impassioned plea on Fred&#8217;s behalf.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not want to testify against my husband, nor do I want him prosecuted.  I believe our trouble was caused as much by me as by my husband.  I want to go back to him and begin all over.&quot;</p>
<p>Judge Stephen G. Long agreed she should have that chance, saying, &quot;This is a very remarkable affair, but if both parties are willing to forgive and forget and to endeavor to patch up their broken lives, I think the kindest thing for this court to do is to give McElrath a chance.&quot;</p>
<p>The charge was dismissed, and the McElraths left the courtroom with their arms wrapped around each other.  Lena&#8217;s wounds were expected to heal completely with time, though Fred would be forever incapacitated by the bullet, still lodged near his spine.</p></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/03/19/a-second-chance/">A Second Chance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/03/19/a-second-chance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Sunday Paper</title>
		<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/03/12/the-sunday-paper/</link>
					<comments>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/03/12/the-sunday-paper/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2008 20:02:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[boxing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laxatives]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slow news day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>In the past two weeks, I&#8217;ve come to understand why Kim usually waits until Fridays to post her 1947p stories. Ever since this leap year, I&#8217;ve found myself with the Sunday paper, which, while jam-packed with Bullock&#8217;s ads, real estate ventures, and fashion spreads (this week, an entire section devoted to shoes!), is rather short&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/03/12/the-sunday-paper/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">The Sunday Paper</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/03/12/the-sunday-paper/">The Sunday Paper</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p>
In the past two weeks, I&#8217;ve come to understand why Kim usually waits until Fridays to post her 1947p stories.  Ever since this leap year, I&#8217;ve found myself with the Sunday paper, which, while jam-packed with Bullock&#8217;s ads, real estate ventures, and fashion spreads (this week, an entire section devoted to shoes!), is rather short on crime and mayhem.  After all, who wants to dwell on such things on the Christian day of rest?
</p>
<p>
And after the stories of the past two days, perhaps there&#8217;s some sense in that.  Unable to top the likes of baby farms and superman love cults, I suppose it&#8217;s fair to say that I&#8217;m feeling a little blocked.
</p>
<p>
<img loading="lazy" src="//farm4.static.flickr.com/3109/2328937071_514aa76ae5.jpg" alt="figlaxative" width="374" height="436" />
</p>
<p>
California fig laxative:Â  it &quot;can&#8217;t harm children.&quot;Â  If that&#8217;s not a ringing endorsement, I don&#8217;t know what is.
</p>
<p>
<img loading="lazy" src="//farm4.static.flickr.com/3161/2329760336_dd24f62c59_m.jpg" alt="lewtendler" width="141" height="240" align="right" />
</p>
<p>
&nbsp;
</p>
<p>
&nbsp;
</p>
<p>
&nbsp;
</p>
<p>
&nbsp;
</p>
<p>
&nbsp;
</p>
<p>
&nbsp;
</p>
<p>
&nbsp;
</p>
<p>
&nbsp;
</p>
<p>
&nbsp;
</p>
<p>
&nbsp;
</p>
<p>
And take a look at this plug for Jewish boxing legend Lew Tendler, as he prepares for his upcoming bout.  Does the &quot;S&quot; stand for Southpaw or sexy?
</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/03/12/the-sunday-paper/">The Sunday Paper</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/03/12/the-sunday-paper/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>You Know, For Kids</title>
		<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/03/05/you-know-for-kids/</link>
					<comments>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/03/05/you-know-for-kids/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2008 18:34:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[los angeles times]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aunt Dolly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[youth activities]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>March 5, 1927 &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160; Beginning in 1923, Aunt Dolly&#8217;s Page occupied its own corner of the Junior Times, a Sunday supplement that urged young Angelenos to try their hands at blank verse, cartooning, and other feats of skill for fabulous prizes. There were also picnics, parades, community service projects, and a near-constant&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/03/05/you-know-for-kids/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">You Know, For Kids</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/03/05/you-know-for-kids/">You Know, For Kids</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p>
March 5, 1927
</p>
<p>
<img loading="lazy" src="//farm4.static.flickr.com/3242/2312172350_2d1592594f_o.jpg" alt="auntdolly" width="414" height="87" align="left" />
</p>
<p>
&nbsp;
</p>
<p>
&nbsp;
</p>
<p>
&nbsp;
</p>
<p>
&nbsp;
</p>
<p>
<img loading="lazy" src="//farm4.static.flickr.com/3171/2311363121_2ccd34fcce.jpg" alt="coupons" width="177" height="462" align="left" />Beginning in 1923, Aunt Dolly&#8217;s Page occupied its own corner of the <em>Junior Times</em>, a Sunday supplement that urged young Angelenos to try their hands at blank verse, cartooning, and other feats of skill for fabulous prizes.  There were also picnics, parades, community service projects, and a near-constant series of elections for the President of the <em>Times</em> Junior Club</p>
<p>Today, Aunt Dolly urged the youngsters to register for the Junior Jubilee, to be held at the Echo Park Recreation Center.  Young readers were tempted with refreshments, a large band, a big show, sports, contests, monkey bars, and a parade.</p>
<p>Boys&#8217; coupons enlisted the tikes in a &quot;best-decorated bike&quot; race and parade, as well as a &quot;Ride-the-Plank&quot; contest, though the wording on girls&#8217; registration forms was equally odd:  &quot;I, (your name here) wish to enter your paper hat contest.  I promise to parade at the Echo Park playground.&quot;</p>
<p>Nothing quite like a forced march in a paper hat to brighten up one&#8217;s Saturday afternoon!
</p>
<p>
The persona of Aunt Dolly was gradually nudged from the Junior Times in the late 1920s, appearing only to write a serial entitled &quot;Snoopy in Do-Do Land.&quot;  The feature abruptly ended in 1931 &#8212; perhaps Aunt Dolly got a buyout?
</p>
<p>
&nbsp;
</p>
<p>
<img loading="lazy" src="//farm3.static.flickr.com/2348/2311363135_10fef06ed9_m.jpg" alt="snoopy" width="240" height="144" />
</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/03/05/you-know-for-kids/">You Know, For Kids</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/03/05/you-know-for-kids/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Why Do You Suppose They Had That Pick, Shovel, and Canvas?&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/27/why-do-you-suppose-they-had-that-pick-shovel-and-canvas/</link>
					<comments>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/27/why-do-you-suppose-they-had-that-pick-shovel-and-canvas/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2008 08:04:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>February 28, 1927 Van Nuys, CA Today, Dr. Burt Fullmer was savagely attacked, after being lured to a cabin in the Princess Auto Camp near Van Nuys. When Fullmer entered the cabin, he was bludgeoned in the head by Dr. J.H. Balzer, while Mary Wade stuck him in the arm with a hypodermic needle full&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/27/why-do-you-suppose-they-had-that-pick-shovel-and-canvas/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">&#8220;Why Do You Suppose They Had That Pick, Shovel, and Canvas?&#8221;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/27/why-do-you-suppose-they-had-that-pick-shovel-and-canvas/">&#8220;Why Do You Suppose They Had That Pick, Shovel, and Canvas?&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>February 28, 1927<br />
Van Nuys, CA</p>
<p>Today, Dr. Burt Fullmer was savagely attacked, after being lured to a cabin in the Princess Auto Camp near Van Nuys.  When Fullmer entered the cabin, he was bludgeoned in the head by Dr. J.H. Balzer, while Mary Wade stuck him in the arm with a hypodermic needle full of morphine.  Fullmer fought them off, and the three rolled out the cabin door where they attracted the notice of neighboring campers.</p>
<p>Responding officers discovered a shovel, rope, and canvas in the cabin, and charged Balzer and Wade with suspicion of assault with a deadly weapon and assault to commit murder.</p>
<p>And you&#8217;ll never guess the motive for the attack.  No, seriously.  You will never guess it.</p>
<p>The attack on Fullmer was the latest in a series of power plays between warring factions of a splinter sect of the Seventh Day Adventist Church.</p>
<p>Fullmer had recently been excommunicated from the Seventh Day Adventist Church, along with many others, for following the teachings of Mrs. Margaret Rowan, a self-proclaimed prophet who, the Times says, &#8220;rather startled the world by predicting its sudden finish two years ago.&#8221;</p>
<p>The excommunicated started the Seventh Day Adventist Reformed Church.  However, the fledgling church ran into trouble in a hurry.</p>
<p>As President and Treasurer of the church, Fullmer found himself at odds with Rowan.  He said, &#8220;I began to suspect that maybe things weren&#8217;t just right after her prediction failed to come true&#8230; I began investigating Mrs. Rowan&#8217;s activities and the things that developed caused a split in our ranks.&#8221;  Fullmer claimed he had dirt on Rowan, and her followers intended for it never to come out.  &#8220;They were planning to kill me.  Why do you suppose they had that pick, shovel, and canvas for if it wasn&#8217;t to bury me?&#8221;</p>
<p>In turn, Balzer claimed that Fullmer had been trying to wrest control of the group and had embezzled the church&#8217;s funds.  Balzer said, &#8220;We were driven to the limits of desperation by this man.  His persecution has been terrible.&#8221;</p>
<p>Blessed with foresight, Mrs. Rowan skipped town right around this time, prompting a statewide search as police sought her in connection with the beating.  A week later, she surrendered to police, and stood trial with Wade and Balzer.  The three were found guilty, and sentenced to 1 to 10 at San Quentin.</p></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/27/why-do-you-suppose-they-had-that-pick-shovel-and-canvas/">&#8220;Why Do You Suppose They Had That Pick, Shovel, and Canvas?&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/27/why-do-you-suppose-they-had-that-pick-shovel-and-canvas/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Today&#8217;s Adventure:  Tarzan and the Incompetent Burglars</title>
		<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/20/todays-adventure-tarzan-and-the-incompetent-burglars/</link>
					<comments>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/20/todays-adventure-tarzan-and-the-incompetent-burglars/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2008 18:18:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>February 20, 1927 Reseda, CA &#8220;The entire affair is shrouded in mystery,&#8221; said D&#8217;Arnot. &#8220;I have it on the best of authority that neither the police nor the special agents of the general staff have the faintest conception of how it was accomplished. All they know, all that anyone knows, is that Nikolas Rokoff has&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/20/todays-adventure-tarzan-and-the-incompetent-burglars/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Today&#8217;s Adventure:  Tarzan and the Incompetent Burglars</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/20/todays-adventure-tarzan-and-the-incompetent-burglars/">Today&#8217;s Adventure:  Tarzan and the Incompetent Burglars</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>February 20, 1927<br />
Reseda, CA</p>
<p>&#8220;The entire affair is shrouded in mystery,&#8221; said D&#8217;Arnot.  &#8220;I have it on the best of authority that neither the police nor the special agents of the general staff have the faintest conception of how it was accomplished.  All they know, all that anyone knows, is that Nikolas Rokoff has escaped.&#8221; &#8212; from The Beasts of Tarzan</p>
<p>Lord Greystoke bellowed with rage to discover that, while his humble creator, Burroughs, was quite suddenly called away to Ogden, Utah, his offices had been burgled.  It seemed that nothing had been taken, all the papers and the small bit of cash that Burroughs kept onhand remained undisturbed.</p>
<p>However, the office&#8217;s lovely French doors had been jimmied open, and the hinges on the safe battered, as if by a hammer.  Surely this had the stink about it of Nikolas Rokoff, recently escaped from a French prison, and bent on avenging the man whose testimony had locked him away!  </p>
<p>And then, Lord Greystoke dropped his jaw in horror.  He should have realized!  Of course, the bungled burglary was no more than a diversion, meant no doubt, to distract him from Rokoff&#8217;s more sinister designs.  Greystoke burst through the ruined French doors of Burroughs&#8217;s office, and raced home to determine whether his archenemy had kidnapped his wife and son.  Again.</p></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/20/todays-adventure-tarzan-and-the-incompetent-burglars/">Today&#8217;s Adventure:  Tarzan and the Incompetent Burglars</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/20/todays-adventure-tarzan-and-the-incompetent-burglars/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>L.A. Crimes of Passion Revealed!</title>
		<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/19/l-a-crimes-of-passion-revealed/</link>
					<comments>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/19/l-a-crimes-of-passion-revealed/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2008 01:35:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mayhem]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Murder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The wacko file]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[events]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This Thurday at Central Library, LAPL reference librarians Greg Reynolds and Mary McCoy will be sharing ghastly stories of love gone bad in the City of Angels. The mild-mannered Marie Tucker claimed her husband stabbed himself in the stomach while making a ham sandwich &#8211; was it an accident or murder most foul? Who shot&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/19/l-a-crimes-of-passion-revealed/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">L.A. Crimes of Passion Revealed!</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/19/l-a-crimes-of-passion-revealed/">L.A. Crimes of Passion Revealed!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p>This Thurday at Central Library, LAPL reference librarians Greg Reynolds and Mary McCoy will be sharing ghastly stories of love gone bad in the City of Angels.</p>
<ul>
<li>The mild-mannered Marie Tucker claimed her husband stabbed himself in the stomach while making a ham sandwich &#8211; was it an accident or murder most foul?</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>Who shot Fred Oesterreich in his home in 1922?&nbsp; Was it his lusty wife, Dolly, or her live-in lover, secreted away in an attic love nest?</li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li>And why did Hattie Woolsteen <em>really</em> kill her married lover?</li>
</ul>
<p>Find out this Thursday, and learn the true stories behind some of Los Angeles&#8217;s most notorious crimes of passion.&nbsp;</p>
<address><strong>Los Angeles True Crime:&nbsp; Crimes of Passion</strong></address>
<address><strong>Thursdays @ Central</strong></address>
<address><strong>Central Library, Meeting Room A</strong></address>
<address><strong>Thursday, Feb. 21, 12pm&nbsp;</strong></address>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/19/l-a-crimes-of-passion-revealed/">L.A. Crimes of Passion Revealed!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/19/l-a-crimes-of-passion-revealed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Snow Davis, aka Harry Harpon, aka &#8220;The Sticker&#8221;</title>
		<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/13/snow-davis-aka-harry-harpon-aka-the-sticker/</link>
					<comments>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/13/snow-davis-aka-harry-harpon-aka-the-sticker/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2008 22:45:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Chinatown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kidnapping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Poisoning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The wacko file]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dope fiends]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>February 13, 1927 Chinatown&#160; &#160; The headline read, &#34;TORTURE DEN AND POISON PEN OF SUSPECTED DOPE SLAYER BELIEVED FOUND,&#34; and the story itself contained six missing girls, a basement torture chamber, and a &#34;trick&#34; pencil that could turn into hypodermic needle, chock full of poison, with the flick of a finger. &#160; The villain was&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/13/snow-davis-aka-harry-harpon-aka-the-sticker/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Snow Davis, aka Harry Harpon, aka &#8220;The Sticker&#8221;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/13/snow-davis-aka-harry-harpon-aka-the-sticker/">Snow Davis, aka Harry Harpon, aka &#8220;The Sticker&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<div align="left">February 13, 1927</div>
<div align="left">Chinatown&nbsp;</div>
<div align="left">&nbsp;</div>
<div align="left"><img loading="lazy" width="238" height="203" border="0" align="left" src="//farm3.static.flickr.com/2184/2263112569_bd5cca6f05_o.jpg" alt="dopeslayer" title="dopeslayer" />The headline read, &quot;TORTURE DEN AND POISON PEN OF SUSPECTED DOPE SLAYER BELIEVED FOUND,&quot; and the story itself contained six missing girls, a basement torture chamber, and a &quot;trick&quot; pencil that could turn into hypodermic needle, chock full of poison, with the flick of a finger.</div>
<div align="left">&nbsp;</div>
<div align="left">The villain was none other than Snow Davis, aka Harry Harpon, aka The Sticker, a dope fiend who&#8217;d done time on poison charges in three state prisons in as many years, and had twice been a murder suspect.</div>
<div align="left">&nbsp;</div>
<div align="left">It&#8217;s all quite a lot of build-up for a story that ultimately came to nothing.&nbsp;</div>
<div align="left">&nbsp;</div>
<div align="left">The Chinatown den was discovered when undercover agents heard groans in its vacinity.&nbsp; Their report was passed along to the feds, who prompty raided the joint.&nbsp; In addition to the &quot;poison pencil,&quot; Snow Davis&#8217;s known weapon of choice, they found piles of women&#8217;s clothing and a stack of newspaper clippings from New Orleans.</div>
<div align="left">&nbsp;</div>
<div align="left">However, any former inhabitants had fled.&nbsp; Investigators had been hoping to link Snow to the January disappearances of six girls between the ages of 15 and 20, but it must have been wishful thinking.</div>
<div align="left">&nbsp;</div>
<div align="left">Snow Davis, aka Harry Harpon, aka The Sticker, gets out of Los Angeles unscathed, and the <em>Times</em> never mentions him again.&nbsp;</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/13/snow-davis-aka-harry-harpon-aka-the-sticker/">Snow Davis, aka Harry Harpon, aka &#8220;The Sticker&#8221;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/13/snow-davis-aka-harry-harpon-aka-the-sticker/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Anything for a Bust</title>
		<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/06/anything-for-a-bust/</link>
					<comments>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/06/anything-for-a-bust/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2008 22:14:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[bootlegging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[police]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prohibition]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>February 6, 1927 Over the weekend, the District Attorney&#8217;s crackerjack Prohibition task force proved beyond the shadow of a doubt their devotion to the cause. Then again, after the theatrical busts they staged, it&#8217;s also possible that rum squad head George Contreras and his men simply craved adventure, danger, or an excuse to wear women&#8217;s&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/06/anything-for-a-bust/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Anything for a Bust</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/06/anything-for-a-bust/">Anything for a Bust</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<div align="left">February 6, 1927</div>
<div align="left"></div>
<div align="left"><img loading="lazy" title="rumsquad" src="//farm3.static.flickr.com/2405/2248818007_fd90e711e6_o.jpg" alt="rumsquad" width="201" height="170" align="left" border="0" /> Over the weekend, the District Attorney&#8217;s crackerjack Prohibition task force proved beyond the shadow of a doubt their devotion to the cause.</div>
<div align="left"></div>
<div align="left">Then again, after the theatrical busts they staged, it&#8217;s also possible that rum squad head George Contreras and his men simply craved adventure, danger, or an excuse to wear women&#8217;s clothing.</div>
<div align="left"></div>
<div align="left">The fun started when Contreras and two of his agents entered a home while dressed as telephone repairmen.  When they were unable to find the hooch inside, they flung open the chicken coop in the backyard, and were greeted by three full-grown lions.</div>
<div align="left"></div>
<div align="left">Yes, three full-grown lions.  <em>In a chicken coop.</em></div>
<div align="left"></div>
<div align="left">All three men promptly vaulted over the fence, and sought shelter across the street.  Here, they discovered A. Hernandez&#8217;s 25 gallon still, and arrested him.</div>
<div align="left"></div>
<div align="left">The lions were pets, they later discovered, though &#8220;not particularly fond of strangers.&#8221;</div>
<div align="left"></div>
<div align="left">After the lion incident, Contreras dressed two more of his agents up in women&#8217;s clothing and took them joy-riding to <a title="street" href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=217+e.+61st+st.,+los+angeles,+ca&amp;sll=37.0625,-95.677068&amp;sspn=29.219963,59.765625&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=33.985769,-118.271427&amp;spn=0.007455,0.014591&amp;z=16&amp;iwloc=addr&amp;om=0" target="_blank">217 E. 61st St</a>..  Here, he pulled up to the home of a suspected moonshiner, Raymond Manley, and asked for &#8220;some liquor for the girlfriends.&#8221;  When Manley brought out a bottle, police raided the place and discovered an enormous still, 180 gallons of whiskey, and 39 barrels of mash.</div>
<div align="left"></div>
<div align="left">So, to sum up:  a man crafts a tasty beverage by hand, and goes to jail for his trouble, while the man who raises adult lions, in a chicken coop, no less, walks free.  And our rum squad seems to enjoy playing dress-up a little more than the average adult probably should.</div>
<div align="left"></div>
<div align="left">Up is down, left is right.  Sheesh.</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/06/anything-for-a-bust/">Anything for a Bust</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/02/06/anything-for-a-bust/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Does Not Necessarily Result in Better-Smelling Bandits</title>
		<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/01/30/does-not-necessarily-result-in-better-smelling-bandits/</link>
					<comments>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/01/30/does-not-necessarily-result-in-better-smelling-bandits/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2008 19:05:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Burglary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Robbery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carjacking]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>January 30, 1927 Los Angeles, CA &#160; &#160; Today was a good day to be a bad guy in Los Angeles, and a profitable one, too.&#160; Calls to police flooded in from the terrorized, the carjacked, the held-up, and the home invaded, for a total of 16 robberies and 30 burglaries in a single day.&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/01/30/does-not-necessarily-result-in-better-smelling-bandits/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Does Not Necessarily Result in Better-Smelling Bandits</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/01/30/does-not-necessarily-result-in-better-smelling-bandits/">Does Not Necessarily Result in Better-Smelling Bandits</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<div align="left">January 30, 1927</div>
<div align="left">Los Angeles, CA</div>
<div align="left">&nbsp;</div>
<div align="left"><img loading="lazy" width="500" height="128" border="0" src="//farm3.static.flickr.com/2351/2231367966_50661bef85.jpg" alt="banditry" title="banditry" />&nbsp;</div>
<div align="left">Today was a good day to be a bad guy in Los Angeles, and a profitable one, too.&nbsp; Calls to police flooded in from the terrorized, the carjacked, the held-up, and the home invaded, for a total of 16 robberies and 30 burglaries in a single day.</p>
<p>Poor Catherine Schmidt, a clerk at the Van De Camp bakery at <a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&#038;hl=en&#038;geocode=&#038;q=3601+sunset,+los+angeles,+ca&#038;sll=37.0625,-95.677068&#038;sspn=31.150864,59.765625&#038;ie=UTF8&#038;ll=34.091727,-118.276899&#038;spn=0.007943,0.014591&#038;z=16&#038;om=0" target="_blank" title="sunset">3601 Sunset</a>, was robbed for the second time in a single week.&nbsp; The scar-faced stick-up man made off with $17, and Catherine recognized him as the same guy who&#8217;d rifled through her register just a few days previous.</p>
<p>Drug store owner Charles A. Elliott had already closed up shop when bandits struck, and was spared the indignity of having a gun waved in his face.&nbsp; However, his safe was cracked and $300 liberated, along with 22 pints of medicinal whiskey.&nbsp; Pharmacy grade &#8212; nice!</p>
<p>John S. Smith was held up at Mulholland and Laurel Canyon, and dragged from his car.&nbsp; When the thugs discovered that Smith didn&#8217;t have any money on him, they swiped his hat and coat and cut his ignition wires.&nbsp; Jack Olonglin was also stranded roadside when a carjacking pair set up a roadblock at <a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&#038;hl=en&#038;geocode=&#038;q=wilshire+and+yale,+los+angeles,+ca&#038;sll=34.093255,-118.223534&#038;sspn=0.015886,0.029182&#038;ie=UTF8&#038;ll=34.039876,-118.474653&#038;spn=0.015896,0.029182&#038;z=15&#038;om=0" target="_blank" title="wilshire">Yale and Wilshire</a>, and took $300 and two suitcases of clothing from him before disabling his auto.</p>
<p>K.E. Winters, laundry truck driver, was stalled at Avenue 37 and Dayton when he was set upon by another would-be robber.&nbsp; However, as Winters&nbsp; handed over the money, he whipped up a hard luck story about not being able to cover his bills as it was.&nbsp; His assailant took pity on him, and returned the money, saying, &quot;Oh well.&nbsp; I guess I&#8217;m too soft-hearted to be a bandit anyway.&nbsp; Slip me enought to buy a bed and some eats and I&#8217;ll let you go.&quot;</p>
<p>Can&#8217;t believe that one worked, but nicely played, Mr. Winters.</p></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/01/30/does-not-necessarily-result-in-better-smelling-bandits/">Does Not Necessarily Result in Better-Smelling Bandits</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/01/30/does-not-necessarily-result-in-better-smelling-bandits/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Demon Liquor</title>
		<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/01/23/demon-liquor/</link>
					<comments>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/01/23/demon-liquor/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2008 16:51:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Accidents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[drunk driving]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pasadena]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public intoxication]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>January 23, 1927 Pasadena, CA&#160; &#160; W.H. Latour, a 71-year-old night watchman at the Lamanda Park Citrus Packing Plant in Pasadena, was propped up with a bottle of white lightning when he caught Tom Clark working on his car on the plant grounds.&#160; When Latour told him to leave, Clark nodded, and prepared to set&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/01/23/demon-liquor/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Demon Liquor</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/01/23/demon-liquor/">Demon Liquor</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<div align="left">January 23, 1927</div>
<div align="left">Pasadena, CA&nbsp;</div>
<div align="left">&nbsp;</div>
<div align="left"><img loading="lazy" width="240" height="115" border="0" align="left" src="//farm3.static.flickr.com/2156/2214021308_b29ba6728a_m.jpg" alt="latour" title="latour" />W.H. Latour, a 71-year-old night watchman at the Lamanda Park Citrus Packing Plant in Pasadena, was propped up with a bottle of white lightning when he caught Tom Clark working on his car on the plant grounds.&nbsp; When Latour told him to leave, Clark nodded, and prepared to set off on his way.</p>
<p>But then, Latour became convinced that the car was trying to attack him, and pulled a gun on it.&nbsp; After firing two shots at Clark&#8217;s car, Latour raised his arm to wave off the terrifying apparition and fired again &#8212; directly into his own hand.</p>
<p>Elsewhere in Los Angeles today, another man paid a less gory price for intemperance.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" width="240" height="109" border="0" align="right" src="//farm3.static.flickr.com/2294/2213228409_0225dc4a46_m.jpg" alt="sober" title="sober" />Earlier this month, police were called to <a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&#038;hl=en&#038;geocode=&#038;time=&#038;date=&#038;ttype=&#038;q=mt.+washington+dr.,+los+angeles&#038;sll=37.0625,-95.677068&#038;sspn=31.150864,59.765625&#038;ie=UTF8&#038;ll=34.099332,-118.21641&#038;spn=0.015885,0.029182&#038;z=15&#038;iwloc=addr&#038;om=0" target="_blank" title="mtwashingtondr">Mt. Washington Dr.</a> following reports of a dead body slumped in a car along the side of the road.&nbsp; But James Proffit wasn&#8217;t dead &#8212; only dead drunk, and &quot;there were several dead soldiers around him in the form of empty bottles from which the spirits had fled.&quot;</p>
<p>Today in court, Proffit had some interesting things to say for himself.&nbsp; &quot;It&#8217;s the holidays and festivities that get me in trouble,&quot; Proffit told Municipal Judge Turney.&nbsp; &quot;I was in jail at Thanksgiving for being drunk, and it was the same thing at Christmas and New Year&#8217;s.&nbsp; I wouldn&#8217;t be here now, but my brother got married, and of course, I was there as a guest.&quot;</p>
<p>Turns out, Proffit had forgotten his duty to drive the newlyweds home from the reception.&nbsp; When he swerved off the road and got them all stuck in the mud, the bride and groom decided to walk the rest of the way home, leaving Proffit to fend for himself.&nbsp; Proffit was fined $200.</p></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/01/23/demon-liquor/">Demon Liquor</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/01/23/demon-liquor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
