<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>courtroom drama &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<atom:link href="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/tag/courtroom-drama-4/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/</link>
	<description>Los Angeles De-Mythified</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 18:09:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7</generator>

<image>
	<url>http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-1947logoSquare-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>courtroom drama &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<link>http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Don&#8217;t Get Mad, Get Everything</title>
		<link>http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/08/22/dont-get-mad-get-everything/</link>
					<comments>http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/08/22/dont-get-mad-get-everything/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2007 16:59:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Chaplin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[divorce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[courtroom drama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental cruelty]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Aug. 22, 1927 Hollywood divorces may be ugly today, but the dissolution of the legal bonds between Charlie Chaplin and his child bride, Lita Grey, may have been nastier than K-Fed and Britney, Alec and Kim, and Loni and Burt put together. After divorce proceedings that had dragged on for nearly a year, Chaplin and&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/08/22/dont-get-mad-get-everything/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Don&#8217;t Get Mad, Get Everything</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/08/22/dont-get-mad-get-everything/">Don&#8217;t Get Mad, Get Everything</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<div align="left">Aug. 22, 1927</div>
<div align="left"></div>
<div align="left"><img loading="lazy" title="chaplindivorce1" src="//farm2.static.flickr.com/1414/1203198119_e3bdf4e0e4_m.jpg" alt="chaplindivorce1" width="240" height="202" align="left" border="0" /> Hollywood divorces may be ugly today, but the dissolution of the legal bonds between Charlie Chaplin and his child bride, Lita Grey, may have been nastier than K-Fed and Britney, Alec and Kim, and Loni and Burt put together.</p>
<p>After divorce proceedings that had dragged on for nearly a year, Chaplin and Grey settled out of court today for the staggering sum of nearly $1 million ($11,971,200 USD 2007).Â  $625,000 went to Lita, $200,000 was used to set up trust funds for the couple&#8217;s two babies, and the rest went towards assorted legal and court fees.Â  She lost the house, but got custody of the children.Â  It was, in 1927, the largest divorce settlement ever paid in California history.</p>
<p>Lita was only 18, but she was either exceptionally shrewd or exceptionally wronged.</p>
<p>Wed in Mexico in November 1924, Lita moved out almost exactly two years later.Â  However, the marriage was in trouble quite literally from the beginning.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" title="chaplindivorce2" src="//farm2.static.flickr.com/1030/1204059756_f2594a69a1_m.jpg" alt="chaplindivorce2" width="205" height="233" align="right" border="0" />In her nearly 50-page formal complaint against Chaplin, Grey leveled the following accusations:Â  he&#8217;d forced her to have sex with him before they were married; he&#8217;d told her to get an abortion when he discovered she was pregnant; on their way back to Los Angeles after their wedding, he told her, &#8220;This marriage won&#8217;t last long.Â  I&#8217;ll make you so &#8212; sick of me that you won&#8217;t want to live with me&#8221;; accused her of forcing him into marriage; had an affair with a prominent motion picture actress; told her she was stupid; encouraged her to commit suicide; only took her out 3-4 times during the first two months of their marriage &#8220;for the sake of appearances&#8221;; left her alone on Christmas while he went out and got drunk; threatened her life twice with a loaded revolver; and since their separation, had only given her $27 for milk for the babies.</p>
<p>Apparently, Chaplin decided the money was worth his peace of mind &#8211; he didn&#8217;t even show up in court.Â  Earlier in the year, Chaplin had filed a cross-complaint that denied many of Grey&#8217;s charges, and accused her of excessive partying, relationships with other men, and negligent parenting; however, this complaint was dismissed at the time of the settlement.</p></div>
</div>
</div>
<p><a class="a2a_button_facebook" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fhttps%3A%2F%2Fpensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app%2F2007%2F08%2F22%2Fdont-get-mad-get-everything%2F&amp;linkname=Don%E2%80%99t%20Get%20Mad%2C%20Get%20Everything" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fhttps%3A%2F%2Fpensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app%2F2007%2F08%2F22%2Fdont-get-mad-get-everything%2F&amp;linkname=Don%E2%80%99t%20Get%20Mad%2C%20Get%20Everything" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_button_email" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/email?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fhttps%3A%2F%2Fpensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app%2F2007%2F08%2F22%2Fdont-get-mad-get-everything%2F&amp;linkname=Don%E2%80%99t%20Get%20Mad%2C%20Get%20Everything" title="Email" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=http%3A%2F%2Fhttps%3A%2F%2Fpensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app%2F2007%2F08%2F22%2Fdont-get-mad-get-everything%2F&#038;title=Don%E2%80%99t%20Get%20Mad%2C%20Get%20Everything" data-a2a-url="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/08/22/dont-get-mad-get-everything/" data-a2a-title="Don’t Get Mad, Get Everything"></a></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/08/22/dont-get-mad-get-everything/">Don&#8217;t Get Mad, Get Everything</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/08/22/dont-get-mad-get-everything/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Long Distance Murder</title>
		<link>http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/06/27/the-long-distance-murder/</link>
					<comments>http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/06/27/the-long-distance-murder/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2007 17:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Accidents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Arson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Burning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Central]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[courtroom drama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Earl J. Clark]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; &#160;At 1681 E. Manchester Ave., the tenants were lousy and business was bad.&#160; But George H. Ferlin of 8606 Hickory St. had insurance and a scheme to make all his problems go up in smoke.&#160; One night in August 1925, Ferlin doused everything in gasoline and vacated the premises.&#160; Later in the evening his&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/06/27/the-long-distance-murder/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">The Long Distance Murder</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/06/27/the-long-distance-murder/">The Long Distance Murder</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<div align="left"><img loading="lazy" width="497" height="120" border="0" src="//farm2.static.flickr.com/1086/639707283_f4dd8de210.jpg" alt="ferlinheadline" title="ferlinheadline" />&nbsp;</div>
<div align="left">&nbsp;At <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&#038;hl=en&#038;geocode=&#038;q=1681+e.+manchester+ave.,+los+angeles,+ca&#038;sll=37.0625,-95.677068&#038;sspn=29.163842,58.710937&#038;ie=UTF8&#038;ll=33.961159,-118.306425&#038;spn=0.007439,0.014334&#038;z=16&#038;iwloc=addr&#038;om=1" target="_blank" title="manchester">1681 E. Manchester Ave.</a>, the tenants were lousy and business was bad.&nbsp; But George H. Ferlin of <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&#038;hl=en&#038;geocode=&#038;q=8606+hickory+st..,+los+angeles,+ca&#038;sll=33.961159,-118.306425&#038;sspn=0.007439,0.014334&#038;ie=UTF8&#038;ll=33.96123,-118.235142&#038;spn=0.007439,0.014334&#038;z=16&#038;iwloc=addr&#038;om=1" target="_blank" title="hickory">8606 Hickory St.</a> had insurance and a scheme to make all his problems go up in smoke.&nbsp; One night in August 1925, Ferlin doused everything in gasoline and vacated the premises.&nbsp; Later in the evening his accomplice, 21-year-old Walter Skala, arrived on the scene, ignited the whole mess, and was burned to death for a payoff that probably amounted to a few hundred lousy dollars.</p>
<p>Was it murder?&nbsp; Some folks thought so.&nbsp; In addition to charges for arson and destroying insured property, Ferlin was charged with the murder of Walter Skala, despite the fact that he wished him no harm and was over a mile away at the time Skala sustained his injuries.&nbsp; The charge was issued under an old and little-used California statute that held a person who conspired to commit an unlawful act responsible if another person was indirectly killed as a result of that crime.</p>
<p>At Ferlin&#8217;s trial, the judge instructed the jury to deliberate only on the two lesser charges and acquit on murder.&nbsp; However, the jury ignored him roundly, saying they felt Ferlin was &quot;morally guilty&quot; in Skala&#8217;s death and convicted him of murder.&nbsp; Of course, there were appeals at the District and State level that dragged on for over two years while Ferlin sat in prison.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, there was trouble at home.&nbsp; Ferlin&#8217;s wife, Jean, and her lover, Ivan Hunsacker, appeared in juvenile court on charges of contributing to the delinquency of two minors, Jean&#8217;s children.&nbsp; Apparently, since Ferlin was locked away, Hunsacker had been shacking up with Jean and the kiddies.&nbsp; The couple pled guilty to the charges.</p>
<p>In March 1927, the State Supreme Court announced that Ferlin&#8217;s appeal would be heard, along with three other notorious murder cases.&nbsp; Faithful 1947project readers will be interested to know that Earl J. Clark, aka the <a href="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/redrosekiller" target="_blank" title="redrosekiller">Red Rose Killer</a>, was alongside Ferlin on the docket.&nbsp; Clark would hang at San Quentin later in the year, but things went better for our arsonist.</p>
<p>Today, the court ruled that Ferlin was entitled to a new trial on the murder charge since the jury had disregarded the instructions of the trial judge.&nbsp; Ferlin&#8217;s sentence of 25 years for his other convictions was upheld.&nbsp; The murder beef was eventually dismissed in 1928.</div>
</div>
</div>
<p><a class="a2a_button_facebook" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fhttps%3A%2F%2Fpensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app%2F2007%2F06%2F27%2Fthe-long-distance-murder%2F&amp;linkname=The%20Long%20Distance%20Murder" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fhttps%3A%2F%2Fpensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app%2F2007%2F06%2F27%2Fthe-long-distance-murder%2F&amp;linkname=The%20Long%20Distance%20Murder" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_button_email" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/email?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fhttps%3A%2F%2Fpensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app%2F2007%2F06%2F27%2Fthe-long-distance-murder%2F&amp;linkname=The%20Long%20Distance%20Murder" title="Email" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=http%3A%2F%2Fhttps%3A%2F%2Fpensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app%2F2007%2F06%2F27%2Fthe-long-distance-murder%2F&#038;title=The%20Long%20Distance%20Murder" data-a2a-url="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/06/27/the-long-distance-murder/" data-a2a-title="The Long Distance Murder"></a></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/06/27/the-long-distance-murder/">The Long Distance Murder</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/06/27/the-long-distance-murder/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>12 Angry Men and Women</title>
		<link>http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/05/30/12-angry-men-and-women/</link>
					<comments>http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/05/30/12-angry-men-and-women/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2007 16:25:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mental illness]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Murder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pomona]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Quentin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[courtroom drama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[juvenile delinquency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>May 30, 1927 Pomona&#160; &#160; Today, 16-year-old Durward Wittenmeyer confessed to the murder of Fannie Weigel, the wife of a Pomona confectioner.&#160; It was just a few days since his release from the Whittier State School, a reformatory.&#160; The emotionally disturbed Wittenmeyer said that on his way home from the movies on May 28, he&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/05/30/12-angry-men-and-women/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">12 Angry Men and Women</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/05/30/12-angry-men-and-women/">12 Angry Men and Women</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<div align="left">May 30, 1927</div>
<div align="left">Pomona&nbsp;</div>
<div align="left">&nbsp;</div>
<div align="left"><img loading="lazy" width="217" height="245" border="0" align="left" title="wittenmeyerheadline" alt="wittenmeyerheadline" src="//farm1.static.flickr.com/207/520342772_074626c210_o.jpg" />Today, 16-year-old Durward Wittenmeyer confessed to the murder of Fannie Weigel, the wife of a Pomona confectioner.&nbsp; It was just a few days since his release from the Whittier State School, a reformatory.&nbsp; The emotionally disturbed Wittenmeyer said that on his way home from the movies on May 28, he picked up an automobile spring leaf from a scrap heap, and &quot;got a funny notion to hit someone.&quot;&nbsp; He saw Weigel walking home from the confectionery story, laden with bundles, and struck her twice in the side of the head.&nbsp; And what was the offense that had previously landed Wittenmeyer in juvie?&nbsp; Throwing a rock at a woman&#8217;s head in 1924.</p>
<p>Like a 1927 Veronica Mars, Thelma Sharp, the 17-year-old daughter of a Pomona police detective, helped police pin down the murderer.&nbsp; Working as an usher at the movie theater, she&#8217;d seen Wittenmeyer the night of the murder, and knew of his previous antics.&nbsp; When police followed up on her lead, they found Wittenmeyer&#8217;s distraught father in the midst of soul-searching.&nbsp; The man burst out, &quot;My boy killed that woman.&nbsp; I have been beside myself since yesterday afternoon when I made him confess to me&#8230; I took cleaning fluid and tried to clean the blood off his clothes yesterday afternoon.&quot;<br /><img loading="lazy" width="187" height="425" border="0" align="right" title="wittenmeyeronstand" alt="wittenmeyeronstand" src="//farm1.static.flickr.com/193/520342750_0c73bc26e7_o.jpg" /><br />Without emotion, young Wittenmeyer confessed to the police.&nbsp; A judge declared Wittenmeyer an unfit subject for juvenile court, and he was set to stand trial as an adult.&nbsp; A psychiatric evaluation found the boy emotionally unstable, but sane.&nbsp; However, a team of alienists for the defense begged to differ.&nbsp; Wittenmeyer suffered from a hereditary form of psychosis, they said, and the boy&#8217;s father testified that his wife was known to have hallucinations and that once, she&#8217;d been found wandering naked in an orange grove.&nbsp; Supervisors of the reform schools where Wittenmeyer had previously been an inmate testified to his erratic behavior while in custody.&nbsp; Throughout the proceedings, the boy seemed oblivious, amusing himself by arranging blotters on a table.</p>
<p>As the prosecution and defense rested, the jury was instructed to return one of four verdicts:&nbsp; not guilty, guilty of first degree murder, guilty of second degree murder, or guilty of first degree murder with the recommendation of a life sentence.&nbsp; Although deliberations were expected to be speedy, the jury was deadlocked after the first day with a single hold-out for a not guilty verdict, while the remaining 11 jurors stood in favor of the harshest sentence.</p>
<p>After 33 hours, Judge Fletcher Bowron threatened to replace the jurors unless they returned a verdict by noon the next day.&nbsp; However, the jury&#8217;s vote now stood at 10-2, with another juror in favor of acquittal.&nbsp; The foreman emerged periodically to ask Bowron whether a recommendation for leniency would be granted, and what the sentence was for second-degree murder.&nbsp; Bowron refused to answer his questions, saying that ultimately, the boy&#8217;s sentence was none of their concern.</p>
<p>Finally, after 55 hours of deliberation, the jury returned a verdict that found Wittenmeyer guilty of murder in the second degree, which carried a sentence of 5 years to life, making the boy eligible for parole in 1932.&nbsp; Acquittal would have sent Wittenmeyer to a state mental facility, so while he did not receive the treatment he needed, the jury&#8217;s decision at least spared the teenager from life imprisonment without the possibility of parole.&nbsp; Or did it?</p>
<p>As of November 1949 (the last mention I could find of him), Wittenmeyer was still serving time in San Quentin, having been denied parole on at least four occasions.</p></div>
</div>
</div>
<p><a class="a2a_button_facebook" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fhttps%3A%2F%2Fpensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app%2F2007%2F05%2F30%2F12-angry-men-and-women%2F&amp;linkname=12%20Angry%20Men%20and%20Women" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fhttps%3A%2F%2Fpensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app%2F2007%2F05%2F30%2F12-angry-men-and-women%2F&amp;linkname=12%20Angry%20Men%20and%20Women" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_button_email" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/email?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fhttps%3A%2F%2Fpensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app%2F2007%2F05%2F30%2F12-angry-men-and-women%2F&amp;linkname=12%20Angry%20Men%20and%20Women" title="Email" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=http%3A%2F%2Fhttps%3A%2F%2Fpensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app%2F2007%2F05%2F30%2F12-angry-men-and-women%2F&#038;title=12%20Angry%20Men%20and%20Women" data-a2a-url="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/05/30/12-angry-men-and-women/" data-a2a-title="12 Angry Men and Women"></a></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/05/30/12-angry-men-and-women/">12 Angry Men and Women</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/05/30/12-angry-men-and-women/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Moo-tion Carried</title>
		<link>http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/04/11/moo-tion-carried/</link>
					<comments>http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/04/11/moo-tion-carried/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2007 15:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Antelope Valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cattle rustlers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[courtroom drama]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[grand larceny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[livestock]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Accused of stealing four cows from Lancaster rancher J.L. Armstrong, Percy Sweet, Samuel Thomason, and Chalice Thomason first came to trial early in 1927.&#160; Due to some uncertainty about the physical appearance of the stolen cows, however, the jury was unable to reach a verdict&#160;for the suspected cattle rustlers. &#160; Deputy District Attorney Ryan then&#160;convinced&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/04/11/moo-tion-carried/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Moo-tion Carried</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/04/11/moo-tion-carried/">Moo-tion Carried</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<div align="left">
<div><img loading="lazy" width="299" height="500" border="0" align="left" src="//farm1.static.flickr.com/198/454405659_3a08c79ff0.jpg" alt="vivianthecow" title="vivianthecow" />Accused of stealing four cows from Lancaster rancher J.L. Armstrong, Percy Sweet, Samuel Thomason, and Chalice Thomason first came to trial early in 1927.&nbsp; Due to some uncertainty about the physical appearance of the stolen cows, however, the jury was unable to reach a verdict&nbsp;for the suspected cattle rustlers. </div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div>Deputy District Attorney Ryan then&nbsp;convinced Judge Stephens that he could have moved&nbsp;the jurors&nbsp;to a conviction had they&nbsp;gotten to see&nbsp;the cows for themselves. &nbsp;When the defendants&#8217; attorney, Guy Eddie, refused to accept photographs of the stolen cattle as evidence in the retrial, Ryan retorted, &quot;Then we will produce the cow in court.&quot;</div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div>Stephens signed an order commanding one of the cows to appear as a silent witness in the grand larceny trial.&nbsp; Why the cow was to be listed as a witness for the state, rather than evidence, is anyone&#8217;s guess.</p>
<p>And so, Vivian, one of the abducted cows, appeared with her calf in the Hall of Justice on April 11.&nbsp; The bovine witness was unwilling to take a freight elevator to the courtroom, so the jurors came to her, and court reconvened in the Hall&#8217;s basement.&nbsp;&nbsp; While on the stand, Vivian made nice with Judge Stephens by&nbsp;licking his ear, prompting Guy Eddie to joke, &quot;I protest!&nbsp; It is apparent that the witness is trying to reach the judge.&quot; </p>
<p>In the end, Ryan&#8217;s strategy seems to have been effective.&nbsp; The Thomason brothers were sentenced to San Quentin for 1-10 years, while Sweet received five years probation on May 23, 1927.</p></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p><a class="a2a_button_facebook" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/facebook?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fhttps%3A%2F%2Fpensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app%2F2007%2F04%2F11%2Fmoo-tion-carried%2F&amp;linkname=Moo-tion%20Carried" title="Facebook" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_button_twitter" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/twitter?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fhttps%3A%2F%2Fpensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app%2F2007%2F04%2F11%2Fmoo-tion-carried%2F&amp;linkname=Moo-tion%20Carried" title="Twitter" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_button_email" href="https://www.addtoany.com/add_to/email?linkurl=http%3A%2F%2Fhttps%3A%2F%2Fpensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app%2F2007%2F04%2F11%2Fmoo-tion-carried%2F&amp;linkname=Moo-tion%20Carried" title="Email" rel="nofollow noopener" target="_blank"></a><a class="a2a_dd addtoany_share_save addtoany_share" href="https://www.addtoany.com/share#url=http%3A%2F%2Fhttps%3A%2F%2Fpensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app%2F2007%2F04%2F11%2Fmoo-tion-carried%2F&#038;title=Moo-tion%20Carried" data-a2a-url="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/04/11/moo-tion-carried/" data-a2a-title="Moo-tion Carried"></a></p><p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/04/11/moo-tion-carried/">Moo-tion Carried</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>http://https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/04/11/moo-tion-carried/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
