<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="https://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="https://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>mail fraud &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<atom:link href="https://1947project.com/tag/mail-fraud/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://1947project.com/</link>
	<description>Los Angeles De-Mythified</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 21:38:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://1947project.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-1947logoSquare-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>mail fraud &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<link>https://1947project.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The Check Is In The Mail</title>
		<link>https://1947project.com/2007/11/13/the-check-is-in-the-mail/</link>
					<comments>https://1947project.com/2007/11/13/the-check-is-in-the-mail/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lynn Peril]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2007 19:16:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crimes against property]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lynn Peril]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[veterans]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dancers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[forgery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mail fraud]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>November 13, 1927Monrovia A dead dancer,her restaurateur ex-husband, and a World War I flying ace: it was a cast of characters that wouldn&#8217;t be out of place in the pulpiest fiction. La Monte McGinnis, currently a Major in the Army Reserve and &#34;one of the earliest American aviators to see service with a famous French&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://1947project.com/2007/11/13/the-check-is-in-the-mail/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">The Check Is In The Mail</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/11/13/the-check-is-in-the-mail/">The Check Is In The Mail</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/lperil/2005326511/" title="The Check Is In the Mail by peril61, on Flickr"><img loading="lazy" src="//farm3.static.flickr.com/2219/2005326511_d1e429460b_o.jpg" width="300" height="165" alt="The Check Is In the Mail" /></a></p>
<p>November 13, 1927<br />Monrovia  </p>
<p>A dead dancer,her restaurateur ex-husband, and a World War I flying ace:  it was a cast of characters that wouldn&#8217;t be out of place in the pulpiest fiction. La Monte McGinnis, currently a Major in the Army Reserve and<br />
&quot;one of the earliest American aviators to see service with a famous French Flying squadron,&quot; was arrested today on suspicion of forgery and mail fraud.   </p>
<p>At some point in the past (detectives<br />
didn&#8217;t say just when), McGinnis met Mr. and Mrs. S.S. Schwartz in New York. Schwartz owned a restaurant; his wife, Tommasine Fabri, was a &quot;French dancer.&quot; After the Schwartzes divorced, Fabri moved to Los Angeles where she seems to have become reacquainted with McGinnis. The change of climate was supposed to help her regain her<br />
health, but Fabri died in August. She had been receiving payments from her ex-husband. McGinnis apparently saw no reason to chase this cash cow away by telling Schwartz of his ex-wife&#8217;s death. Instead, he signed Fabri&#8217;s name to &quot;numerous requests&quot; for money sent to Schwartz. According to detectives, Schwartz in turn mailed his dead<br />
ex-wife $1800 (approximately $22,000 in 2007 dollars).   </p>
<p>Several weeks ago, friends stopped into Schwartz&#8217;s New York eatery and informed him<br />
of Fabri&#8217;s death. Schwartz hightailed it to Los Angeles, where he initiated the search that ended with McGinnis&#8217;s arrest.</p>
<p>McGinnis admitted writing the letters to Schwartz, but said it was at Fabri&#8217;s<br />
request. &quot;Before Miss Fabri died she asked me to look after her little girl until such time as I could get in touch with her<br />
grandparents in Paris, France.&quot; Fabri apparently left no address for them; McGinnis claimed to have contacted the &quot;prefecture of police in Paris&quot; concerning their whereabouts but received no<br />
reply. &quot;The money I received from Schwartz for Renee&#8217;s living and school expenses were due Miss Fabri anyway,&quot; he claimed. &quot;She told me that she had loaned Schwartz money to start the restaurant business in New York. When they were divorced Miss Fabri asked for her money but agreed to accept a certain amount each month. . . . Miss Fabri told me this shortly before she died and asked me to send for the money and use it for Renee.&quot;</p>
<p>In case his sterling qualities as a protector of little girls failed to move police, McGinnis then stated he was a disabled war veteran, who contracted tuberculosis as a result of being gassed overseas.   The case was turned over to Federal authorities for further investigation.  </p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/11/13/the-check-is-in-the-mail/">The Check Is In The Mail</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://1947project.com/2007/11/13/the-check-is-in-the-mail/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
