<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="https://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="https://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>vroman&#8217;s &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/vromans/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Los Angeles De-Mythified</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 19:38:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-1947logoSquare-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>vroman&#8217;s &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>To Do: Prune Your Roses in Memory of Beth Short</title>
		<link>/2008/01/15/to-do-prune-your-roses-in-memory-of-beth-short/</link>
					<comments>/2008/01/15/to-do-prune-your-roses-in-memory-of-beth-short/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2008 19:03:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Black Dahlia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crime Bus Tours]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Elizabeth Short]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[doodah parade]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vroman's]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Gentle reader, Today is a terrible day in Los Angeles history, the 61st anniversary of the morning when Elizabeth Short, soon to be infamous as the Black Dahlia, was discovered dead and cut in two in a vacant lot in Leimert Park. Each January 15, our friend and Dahlia-ologist Larry Harnisch likes to prune his &#8230; <a href="/2008/01/15/to-do-prune-your-roses-in-memory-of-beth-short/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">To Do: Prune Your Roses in Memory of Beth Short</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>Gentle reader,</p>
<p>Today is a terrible day in Los Angeles history, the 61st anniversary of the morning when Elizabeth Short, soon to be infamous as the Black Dahlia, was discovered dead and cut in two in a vacant lot in Leimert Park. Each January 15, our friend and Dahlia-ologist Larry Harnisch likes to prune his roses and think of Beth. Richard already pruned our roses this morning, and as they come back to lovely life we will remember this little lost girl. She would have been 83 years old, had she lived.</p>
<p>On Sunday, the Esotouric bus rolled south from <a href="https://www.vromansbookstore.com/" target="_blank">Vroman&#8217;s Bookstore</a> with a full bus of charming people for the debut of Richard&#8217;s new manifestation of our flagship tour THE REAL BLACK DAHLIA. We were seen off by the delightful Queen Mickie, taking a break from her Doodah Parade preparations to christen the bus with champagne&#8230; bubblebath! Then we headed downtown, to explore the psychology and deep mysteries of Beth Short&#8217;s last hours, visiting the places she frequented, examining the characters who touched her, in life and in death and coming to some understanding of who this strange girl was and what brought her to Los Angeles and her early death. </p>
<p>See photos from this tour here:<br /><a href="https://blackdahliavromans1-13-08.notlong.com/" target="_blank">https://blackdahliavromans1-13-08.notlong.com/</a></p>
<p>And see Queen Mickie in the Doodah Parade next Sunday:<br /><a href="https://www.pasadenadoodahparade.info/" target="_blank">https://www.pasadenadoodahparade.info/</a></p>
<p>This Saturday, 1/19, we offer my personal favorite of our true crime tours, BLOOD AND DUMPLINGS, a criminal and gastronomical excursion into the deeply bizarre criminal and cultural history of the San Gabriel Valley. Meet lions and nazis and hypodermic-jabbing lesbians, religious zealots obsessed with pyramid power, a lesser-known Manson Family victim, James Ellroy&#8217;s iconic murdered mother Geneva, Phil Spector and his hillside castle, deadly trailer parks and actual sea monsters, who will keep you company as you gobble down a dumpling feast from 101 Noodle Express, one of Jonathan Gold&#8217;s top LA restaurants. Join us do, and reserve your spot today by emailing me or buying online at <a href="https://www.esotouric.com/bnd-1-19-08 " target="_blank">https://www.esotouric.com/bnd-1-19-08 </a></p>
<p>As always, we offer 15% off for KCRW members, and a $30 discount when you purchase a 4-tour Season Pass, which can be applied retroactively for folks who have ridden a recent tour. Email for more info or visit the <a href="https://www.esotouric.com/" target="_blank">website</a> to reserve your spot on the unpredictable floating LA think tank that is the Esotouric bus. &nbsp;</p>
<p>yrs,<br />Kim</p>
<p>Upcoming Esotouric bus tour schedule (new tours starred):<br />Sat Jan 19- Blood &amp; Dumplings San Gabriel Valley Crime Bus Tour<br />San Jan 26- Weird West Adams Crime Bus Tour<br />Sat Feb 2- Where the Action Was Hollywood Rock and Roll Tour<br />*Sat Feb 16- Wild Wild West Side Crime Bus Tour<br />*Sat Feb 23- Reyner Banham Loves Los Angeles: The Many Downtowns<br />*Sat Mar 1- Reyner Banham Loves Los Angeles: Route 66 (on Banham&#8217;s birthday weekend)<br />*Sat Mar 8- Raymond Chandler&#8217;s Bay City (West Los Angeles Chandler tour)<br />Sun Mar 9- Haunts of a Dirty Old Man: Charles Bukowski&#8217;s Los Angeles (on the anniversary of his death)<br />Sat Mar 15- Vroman&#8217;s Bookstore presents Pasadena Confidential</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2008/01/15/to-do-prune-your-roses-in-memory-of-beth-short/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
