<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="https://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="https://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>jacob adelman &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<atom:link href="https://1947project.com/tag/jacob-adelman-2/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://1947project.com/</link>
	<description>Los Angeles De-Mythified</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 19:46:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://1947project.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-1947logoSquare-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>jacob adelman &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<link>https://1947project.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>AP feature: Crime tours take passengers through LA&#8217;s criminal past</title>
		<link>https://1947project.com/2007/05/07/ap-feature-crime-tours-take-passengers-through-las-criminal-past/</link>
					<comments>https://1947project.com/2007/05/07/ap-feature-crime-tours-take-passengers-through-las-criminal-past/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2007 04:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Black Dahlia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crime Bus Tours]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raymond chandler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san gabriel valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jacob adelman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>by Jacob Adelman for the Associated Press (AP Photo/Damian Dovarganes) Above: Kelly Kuvo, the Blonde Dahlia &#160; LOS ANGELES &#8212; A dismembered wannabe starlet. A girl buried under her family&#8217;s home. A rattlesnake used as a weapon. The scenes of those crimes are stops on a series of Southern California bus tours that eschew the&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://1947project.com/2007/05/07/ap-feature-crime-tours-take-passengers-through-las-criminal-past/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">AP feature: Crime tours take passengers through LA&#8217;s criminal past</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/05/07/ap-feature-crime-tours-take-passengers-through-las-criminal-past/">AP feature: Crime tours take passengers through LA&#8217;s criminal past</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>by Jacob Adelman for the Associated Press (AP Photo/Damian Dovarganes)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/richardschave/487586327/" title="Photo Sharing"><img loading="lazy" width="500" height="375" border="0" src="//farm1.static.flickr.com/170/487586327_8fd5644edb.jpg" alt="Kelly at Marlowe's Office Building" /></a></p>
<p align="right"><strong>Above: Kelly Kuvo, the Blonde Dahlia</strong> &nbsp;</p>
<p>LOS ANGELES &#8212; A dismembered wannabe starlet. A girl buried under her family&#8217;s home. A rattlesnake used as a weapon.</p>
<p>The scenes of those crimes are stops on a series of Southern California bus tours that eschew the usual stars&#8217; homes and theme parks to offer passengers a peak at the region&#8217;s dark side.</p>
<p>&quot;They&#8217;re aimed at the history geek sort of people,&quot; said Kelly Kuvo, who wears a black veil and other vintage accouterments during the trips she leads for tour company Esotouric.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s &quot;crime bus&quot; tours plumb the grisly, blood-soaked pasts of now quiet Southern California neighborhoods and nondescript strip malls.</p>
<p>Similar trips elsewhere take passengers deep into cities&#8217; gory pasts, including Washington&#8217;s &quot;Bad Olde Days&quot; chronicling crime in the nation&#8217;s capital and &quot;Sinister London&quot; that follows the steps of Jack the Ripper.</p>
<p>&quot;When people die in a place, it does change that place forever,&quot; said Esotouric guide and co-founder Kim Cooper. &quot;Just because the people wandering around the neighborhood may not be aware of it, it doesn&#8217;t mean it&#8217;s not a good idea for people who are interested in history to revive those memories.&quot;</p>
<p>John G. Cawelti, who writes about the seductiveness of violent crime tales in his book &quot;Mystery, Violence, and Popular Culture,&quot; said the tours play into people&#8217;s fears of death and catastrophe.</p>
<p>&quot;We live in an age where the worst kinds of things can happen to anybody,&quot; Cawelti said. &quot;Walk down the street and something blows up and all of a sudden you lost your life or lost a leg. The fact that somebody else went through this becomes a surrogate &ndash; a magical way of charming away the fear of the possibility.&quot;</p>
<p>Esotouric&#8217;s most popular tour explores 1947 Los Angeles by zeroing in on the murder of Elizabeth Short &ndash; a.k.a. &quot;Black Dahlia&quot; &ndash; who came to Hollywood in search of fame but wound up the victim of an infamous unsolved murder.</p>
<p>One stop is a ground-floor storefront on a desolate downtown street that now boasts a sign reading, &quot;Club Galaxy &ndash; 100 Beautiful Girls.&quot;</p>
<p>In 1947, when it was a bistro called &quot;The Crown Grill,&quot; it was the last place Short was seen before her dismembered body was discovered miles away in a south Los Angeles neighborhood.</p>
<p>&quot;She was friendly with the bartenders and with some of the waitresses, so people recognized her and remembered her,&quot; Cooper said. &quot;The problem of course is that everybody at the Crown Grill immediately became suspects.&quot;</p>
<p>Passengers are also introduced to lesser known crimes from the same year, such as the attempted carjacking in Hollywood of an 18-year-old movie theater cashier named Ginevra Knight, who shot her assailant dead.</p>
<p>&quot;It&#8217;s the criminal history of 1947 L.A. and how women felt going out at night in the hysteria of an unsolved murder,&quot; Cooper said.</p>
<p>The &quot;Blood and Dumplings&quot; tour through San Gabriel Valley suburbs, meanwhile, passes the home where a young bride-to-be was buried in 1969 by her uncle after he shot her to death in a jealous rage at the end of their affair.</p>
<p>It also cruises by an intersection where a man named Raymond James bought a rattlesnake he let bite his wife in 1935 so he could cash in on her insurance policy. When she didn&#8217;t die, he had an accomplice finish the job by drowning her in their fish pond.</p>
<p>Esotouric grew out of a Web log Cooper started in 2005, when she set out to retell a true-crime tale from each day of 1947. She and her collaborators soon started offering tours of those scenes and the sites of other crimes.</p>
<p>A tour that revisits the life and literature of Raymond Chandler, whose fictional characters inhabit the region&#8217;s underworld, was added to the menu of crime junkets when the company was started earlier this year.</p>
<p>Tour participant Bob Nickum, 59, a school district business manager, said seeing the sites of past crimes made him look at familiar places in a new way.</p>
<p>&quot;It&#8217;s just very interesting to drive around the area and to see things I may have passed by many times and maybe not known what happened there,&quot; said Nickum, who, like most passengers, lives in Southern California.</p>
<p>&quot;It makes things a little more interesting &ndash; vivid &ndash; to know about something that intense that took place in a calm, peaceful neighborhood,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a title="Photo Sharing" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/richardschave/487557160/"><img loading="lazy" width="500" height="375" border="0" alt="Nathan Heather and Kelly" src="//farm1.static.flickr.com/168/487557160_02588d149e.jpg" /></a></p>
<p align="right"><strong>Nathan Marsak, chess shark Heather and Kelly at the Hotel Barclay<br /></strong></p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/05/07/ap-feature-crime-tours-take-passengers-through-las-criminal-past/">AP feature: Crime tours take passengers through LA&#8217;s criminal past</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://1947project.com/2007/05/07/ap-feature-crime-tours-take-passengers-through-las-criminal-past/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blood &#038; Dumplings Crime Bus Podcast</title>
		<link>https://1947project.com/2007/03/28/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-podcast/</link>
					<comments>https://1947project.com/2007/03/28/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-podcast/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2007 06:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crime Bus Tours]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san gabriel valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Gabriel Valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jacob adelman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lana clarkson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phil spector]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jacob Adelman of the venerable AP rode along with the gang on the Blood &#38; Dumplings Crime Bus Tour on St. Patrick&#8217;s Day, and produced a delightful little audio document of the day for the AP&#8217;s youth-oriented asap section. It includes an overview of the tour, some excerpted crime stories from the tour, and interviews&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://1947project.com/2007/03/28/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-podcast/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Blood &#038; Dumplings Crime Bus Podcast</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/03/28/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-podcast/">Blood &#038; Dumplings Crime Bus Podcast</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>Jacob Adelman of the venerable AP rode along with the gang on the Blood &amp; Dumplings Crime Bus Tour on St. Patrick&#8217;s Day, and produced a delightful little audio document of the day for the AP&#8217;s youth-oriented asap section. It includes an overview of the tour, some excerpted crime stories from the tour, and interviews with a few of the delightful passengers. Why would otherwise normal people choose to spend their Saturday hearing tales of mayhem and horror? <a href="https://asap.ap.org/stories/1330755.s" target="_blank">Click slowly</a> and see&#8230;.</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/03/28/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-podcast/">Blood &#038; Dumplings Crime Bus Podcast</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://1947project.com/2007/03/28/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-podcast/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
