<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="https://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="https://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>attempted murder &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<atom:link href="https://1947project.com/category/crimes-against-persons-15/attempted-murder-3/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://1947project.com/</link>
	<description>Los Angeles De-Mythified</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 21:34:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://1947project.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-1947logoSquare-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>attempted murder &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<link>https://1947project.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>A Second Chance</title>
		<link>https://1947project.com/2008/03/19/a-second-chance/</link>
					<comments>https://1947project.com/2008/03/19/a-second-chance/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2008 18:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[attempted murder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[attempted suicide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Domestic Violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[long beach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>March 19, 1927 Long Beach, CA Fred and Lela McElrath had been married for 25 years, and raised three children together, now grown. But just as the couple should have been settling down into contented empty nesthood, a violent disagreement nearly destroyed it all. Fred wanted to leave Long Beach for Freewater, Oregon, where they&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://1947project.com/2008/03/19/a-second-chance/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">A Second Chance</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2008/03/19/a-second-chance/">A Second Chance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>March 19, 1927<br />
Long Beach, CA</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="//farm4.static.flickr.com/3103/2345049446_6a45978606_m.jpg" alt="longbeachshooting" width="240" height="217" align="left" />Fred and Lela McElrath had been married for 25 years, and raised three children together, now grown.  But just as the couple should have been settling down into contented empty nesthood, a violent disagreement nearly destroyed it all.</p>
<p>Fred wanted to leave Long Beach for Freewater, Oregon, where they owned a ranch; however, Lela was determined to stay put.  She moved out of their home at <a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=45+atlantic+avenue,+los+angeles,+ca&amp;sll=37.0625,-95.677068&amp;sspn=29.219963,59.765625&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=33.769462,-118.185081&amp;spn=0.007474,0.014591&amp;z=16" target="_blank" title="atlantic">45 Atlantic Avenue</a>, and Fred spent nearly a week trying to track her down.  On March 18, they finally agreed to meet at a neutral location, their daughter&#8217;s home at 32 Neptune Place, and try to talk things through.</p>
<p>However, Lela refused to reconsider, and walked away from the argument.  As she was descending the stairs in her daughter&#8217;s house, Fred pulled out a gun and shot her twice in the back before turning the gun on himself, firing into his mouth.  The shots didn&#8217;t kill Lena, and when she was admitted to Seaside Hospital, it was assumed that she would recover.  However, Fred was barely clinging to life, and in fact, police arriving on the scene initially believed him dead.</p>
<p>Today, things looked drastically different.  A bullet was lodged behind Fred&#8217;s left ear, but doctors expected that he would make a full recovery &#8212; and in all likelihood, be left to stand trial for his wife&#8217;s murder.  The shots fired into his wife&#8217;s back had punctured her right lung, and she was not expected to live.  Authorities stood watch at Fred&#8217;s bed, waiting to charge him either with murder or attempted murder.</p>
<p>Shockingly, the story has a moderately happy ending.  On April 11, a frail Lena McElrath, appeared at her husband&#8217;s preliminary hearing and was helped to the stand by her son, where she made an impassioned plea on Fred&#8217;s behalf.</p>
<p>&quot;I do not want to testify against my husband, nor do I want him prosecuted.  I believe our trouble was caused as much by me as by my husband.  I want to go back to him and begin all over.&quot;</p>
<p>Judge Stephen G. Long agreed she should have that chance, saying, &quot;This is a very remarkable affair, but if both parties are willing to forgive and forget and to endeavor to patch up their broken lives, I think the kindest thing for this court to do is to give McElrath a chance.&quot;</p>
<p>The charge was dismissed, and the McElraths left the courtroom with their arms wrapped around each other.  Lena&#8217;s wounds were expected to heal completely with time, though Fred would be forever incapacitated by the bullet, still lodged near his spine.</p></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2008/03/19/a-second-chance/">A Second Chance</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://1947project.com/2008/03/19/a-second-chance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Patricide Interrupted</title>
		<link>https://1947project.com/2008/02/16/patricide-interrupted/</link>
					<comments>https://1947project.com/2008/02/16/patricide-interrupted/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2008 04:21:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[attempted murder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beach Cities]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mystery]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The wacko file]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.1947redux.richardschave.com/2008/02/16/patricide-interrupted/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>February 15, 1927 San Pedro It&#8217;s a mysterious case indeed that enmeshes Mr. Alvin Hyder, wealthy inventor of diesel engines and proprietor of the motorship Nora, working the Channel Islands trade, and his daughter Nora Thomas, 22, wife of a local grocery man. Seems that Nora went into her father&#8217;s room at 2315 South Grand&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://1947project.com/2008/02/16/patricide-interrupted/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Patricide Interrupted</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2008/02/16/patricide-interrupted/">Patricide Interrupted</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p>
February 15, 1927<br />
San Pedro</p>
<p>It&#8217;s a mysterious case indeed that enmeshes Mr. Alvin Hyder, wealthy inventor of diesel engines and proprietor of the motorship Nora, working the Channel Islands trade, and his daughter Nora Thomas, 22, wife of a local grocery man. </p>
<p>Seems that Nora went into her father&#8217;s room at 2315 South Grand Avenue and shot daddy in the head with a .38, before <a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=d&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;saddr=2315+South+Grand+Avenue,+san+pedro,+ca&amp;daddr=2224+South+Grand+Avenue,+san+pedro,+ca&amp;sll=33.725,-118.290288&amp;sspn=0.006568,0.01354&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;ll=33.723625,-118.290255&amp;spn=0.001642,0.003385&amp;z=18" target="_blank">creeping back</a> to her home at 2224 South Grand. Hard-headed Alvin did not die, but repelled the bullet with the force of his personality, sending the leaden lump on a one way trip off his cheekbone, around his face and into the back of his neck, where it remained. Following treatment at San Pedro Emergency Hospital, Alvin returned to Grand Avenue to reflect upon all that had brought him to such a place. </p>
<p>Nora, meanwhile, was arrested and charged with attempted murder. She pled not guilty, with local tongues wagging that this was really all about Nora&#8217;s baby who had died, or maybe $10,000 of her father&#8217;s money that she thought ought be hers. </p>
<p>But in May, the girl was released after the DA declared he had insufficient evidence to convict. Perhaps dad and daughter reconciled in time to take advantage of the Cabrillo Beach grunion run, the dates for which were published in today&#8217;s papers. It&#8217;s the least a captain can do for his ship&#8217;s namesake.
</p>
<p>
[update, July 2008: A descendent of the Hyder family kindly emailed with some additional information to add to this rather mysterious tale. We are always so appreciative when folks with personal knowledge write in to share it.
</p>
<p>
&quot;Alvin was washed overboard off of his fishing boat the Nora II about 1936. A large sneaker wave overturned the boat off of San Nicolas Island. The Coast Guard responded, but his body never turned up. He was 56. His children Nora, Buster, and Alva are all gone now. Nora passed away at age 91 in 1995. She did not discuss her reasons for shooting her father until her 80s. Buster died in &#8217;94 at age 87. Alva died in &#8217;98 at age 73. In 1993, a book was published by the Santa Cruz Island foundation, edited by Marla Daily, entitled &quot;Occasional Paper Number 6.&quot;  She interviewed Buster about our family homesteading on Santa Barbara Island from 1914 to 1929. The National Park Service built a little museum onto the ranger house out there.  In 1993, the TV program &quot;California&#8217;s Gold&quot; did a half hour program on our family reunion and the opening of the little museum.  We had 3 generations there. So, there is a little update to your newspaper clipping.&quot;]
</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2008/02/16/patricide-interrupted/">Patricide Interrupted</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://1947project.com/2008/02/16/patricide-interrupted/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Venice Slasher</title>
		<link>https://1947project.com/2007/11/01/the-venice-slasher/</link>
					<comments>https://1947project.com/2007/11/01/the-venice-slasher/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 01:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[attempted murder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Domestic Violence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Knife]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Venice]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>October 31, 1927 Venice, CA &#160; A gory scene unfolded at the Venice Police Station today as 23-year-old Eddie Berry burst through the front door with a slit throat and passed out on the floor. &#160; An employee of the Venice Speedboat Company, Berry had been working on the Venice Pier when he was accosted&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://1947project.com/2007/11/01/the-venice-slasher/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">The Venice Slasher</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/11/01/the-venice-slasher/">The Venice Slasher</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<div align="left">October 31, 1927</div>
<div align="left">Venice, CA</div>
<div align="left">&nbsp;</div>
<div align="left">A gory scene unfolded at the Venice Police Station today as 23-year-old Eddie Berry burst through the front door with a slit throat and passed out on the floor.</div>
<div align="left">&nbsp;</div>
<div align="left">An employee of the Venice Speedboat Company, Berry had been working on the Venice Pier when he was accosted by a woman packing a knife in her handbag. &nbsp; The dame was Berry&#8217;s sweet wife.&nbsp; She began to argue with him, then drew out her knife and slashed him across the throat, narrowly missing his jugular vein.</div>
<div align="left">&nbsp;</div>
<div align="left">Berry was taken to the emergency room for stitches, while police went out in search of the estranged wife.&nbsp; However, the search was later dropped when Berry refused to press charges.</div>
<div align="left">&nbsp;</div>
<div align="left">Okay, it&#8217;s not much of a Halloween story, but it was this or the story of a few rowdy teens from the Redlands being sent to a YWCA dance to keep them from vandalizing property.&nbsp; Plus, isn&#8217;t &quot;The Venice Slasher&quot; a great name for a would-be murderess?</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/11/01/the-venice-slasher/">The Venice Slasher</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://1947project.com/2007/11/01/the-venice-slasher/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
