<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Preston School of Industry &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<atom:link href="https://1947project.com/tag/preston-school-of-industry/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://1947project.com/</link>
	<description>Los Angeles De-Mythified</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 21:34:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://1947project.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-1947logoSquare-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>Preston School of Industry &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<link>https://1947project.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Ghastly</title>
		<link>https://1947project.com/2007/08/08/ghastly/</link>
					<comments>https://1947project.com/2007/08/08/ghastly/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2007 18:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Beating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Murder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Pasadena]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Preston School of Industry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Whittier State School]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>August 8, 1927&#160; Los Angeles &#160; &#160; Today, 17-year-old Paul Daedler was committed to the Preston School of Industry at Ione on vagrancy charges, and sentenced to remain there until he is 21.&#160; It sounds harsh, until you dig a little deeper. You see, at the tender age of 14, Paul Daedler was accused of&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://1947project.com/2007/08/08/ghastly/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Ghastly</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/08/08/ghastly/">Ghastly</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<div align="left">August 8, 1927&nbsp;</div>
<div align="left">Los Angeles</div>
<div align="left">&nbsp;</div>
<div align="left"><img loading="lazy" width="498" height="121" border="0" src="//farm2.static.flickr.com/1208/1043880079_afcc64c0ec_o.jpg" alt="daedler" title="daedler" /></div>
<div align="left">&nbsp;</div>
<div align="left">Today, 17-year-old Paul Daedler was committed to the Preston School of Industry at Ione on vagrancy charges, and sentenced to remain there until he is 21.&nbsp; It sounds harsh, until you dig a little deeper.</p>
<p>You see, at the tender age of 14, Paul Daedler was accused of one of the grisliest crimes in Pasadena history.&nbsp; Paul came from a good family, but it was reported that he attended the Monroe School for Subnormal Children along with his friend, William &quot;Billie&quot; Forrester.&nbsp; William was adopted, and had been in trouble with the law since he was 12, when he stole $500 from a neighbor and ran off to Arizona.</p>
<p>After school on December 5, 1923, Paul and William were playing with 5-year-old Arthur Martinez, the youngest child of a Pasadena gardener, in an abandoned factory at <a href="http://maps.yahoo.com/broadband#mvt=m&#038;q1=950+s.+raymond+ave.%2C+pasadena%2C+ca&#038;trf=0&#038;lon=-118.148582&#038;lat=34.129746&#038;mag=3" target="_blank" title="raymondave">950 S. Raymond Ave.&nbsp;</a> They had a loaded .22 with them.&nbsp; Exactly what happened in the factory is uncertain, but little Arthur was shot twice in the head and once in the back.&nbsp; The shots didn&#8217;t kill him, though.&nbsp; Scared that Arthur would squeal on them, Paul and William beat him over the head with a brick, tied him to a pole with wire, and left him overnight.&nbsp; When they came back to the factory the next day, (to free him, they said), the boy was dead.</p>
<p>Paul and William went to the police and reported that they &quot;found&quot; Arthur in the factory.&nbsp; However, the police were suspicious of the boys, and after questioning, both confessed.&nbsp; At the inquest, the two expressed little emotion or remorse for what they had done, though the truant officer sitting near them in the courtroom had them shaking in their boots.</p>
<p>On December 20 hearing, Paul was joined by two lawyers, his parents, sisters, and a bevy of witnesses, while William had only his mother by his side.&nbsp; Although Paul had signed two confessions of guilt, his lawyers called witnesses to establish Paul&#8217;s alibi for the time of the killing.&nbsp; Paul also stated that he&#8217;d attended school on December 5, then rode his bicycle to a confirmation class at his church.&nbsp; The pastor of Paul&#8217;s church testified that Paul had been in class, although his schoolteacher, Miss Anna Crane, said that she had not seen Paul after 2pm on the day of the murder.</p>
<p>William was sent to the Preston State School on his 15th birthday to await trial, while Paul was sent to the Whittier State School.&nbsp; Their names and school ID numbers are included in the <a href="http://www.sos.ca.gov/archives/indexes/cya.html" target="_blank" title="californiayouthauthority">California Youth Authority Name Index</a> for 1924 .&nbsp; However, a month after being sentenced to Ione, William produced a confession that absolved Paul of all blame in the killing.&nbsp; In his confession, William said, &quot;I pulled the gun and shot him.&nbsp; Then I though I would put the blame on someone else, so I shot him two more times.&nbsp; I happened to think that whenever Paul Daedler got mad, he always threw bricks, so I decided to throw bricks at Arthur so it would appear that Paul hit him.&quot;</p>
<p>Later, it was revealed that a person interested in the case of Paul Daedler had visited him at the Preston School earlier and persuaded him to change his confession.&nbsp; The possibility that Paul&#8217;s family pressured the poor and unconnected William to take the rap for his friend is not unthinkable.&nbsp; As the boys sat in juvenile facilities, the Daedler family and their lawyers sought a writ of habeas corpus on behalf of Paul, saying that he had been confined to Whittier without a trial before a jury.</p>
<p>The judge upheld Paul&#8217;s detention.</p>
<p>Finally, after serving 17 months at Whittier, Paul was released into the custody of a judge, who ruled that the boy must leave the state, never to return.&nbsp; Paul&#8217;s father, Louis Daedler took him east so he could begin a new life.&nbsp; However, less than two years later, Paul was in County Jail on a vagrancy charge, having hitchhiked his way back to California.&nbsp; And today, he was returned to the juvenile facility.&nbsp; If the case did come to trial at some point, it was not reported in the Times.</p>
<p>Paul Daedler died in Los Angeles on December 21, 1981.&nbsp; William Forrester was paroled from the Preston School on November 19, 1925, and disappeared without a trace. </div>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/08/08/ghastly/">Ghastly</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://1947project.com/2007/08/08/ghastly/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
