<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="https://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="https://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>san gabriel valley &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<atom:link href="https://1947project.com/category/cities/san-gabriel-valley-19/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://1947project.com/</link>
	<description>Los Angeles De-Mythified</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 21:59:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://1947project.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-1947logoSquare-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>san gabriel valley &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<link>https://1947project.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Saturday 9/29 &#8211; Explore the San Gabriel Valley&#8217;s legacy of weird crimes, sea monsters and great eats</title>
		<link>https://1947project.com/2007/09/26/saturday-929-explore-the-san-gabriel-valleys-legacy-of-weird-crimes-sea-monsters-and-great-eats/</link>
					<comments>https://1947project.com/2007/09/26/saturday-929-explore-the-san-gabriel-valleys-legacy-of-weird-crimes-sea-monsters-and-great-eats/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2007 13:41:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crime Bus Tours]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[james ellroy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nazis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san gabriel valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Gabriel Valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phil spector]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Gentle reader, What are you doing Saturday afternoon? Will you be among the lucky citizens exploring the strange secrets of the San Gabriel Valley and feasting on juicy dumplings on a concrete sea monster, or will you bored and kicking yourself for not getting on the Crime Bus? Read on for all you need to&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://1947project.com/2007/09/26/saturday-929-explore-the-san-gabriel-valleys-legacy-of-weird-crimes-sea-monsters-and-great-eats/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Saturday 9/29 &#8211; Explore the San Gabriel Valley&#8217;s legacy of weird crimes, sea monsters and great eats</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/09/26/saturday-929-explore-the-san-gabriel-valleys-legacy-of-weird-crimes-sea-monsters-and-great-eats/">Saturday 9/29 &#8211; Explore the San Gabriel Valley&#8217;s legacy of weird crimes, sea monsters and great eats</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p>Gentle reader,</p>
<p>What are you doing Saturday afternoon? Will you be among the lucky citizens exploring the strange secrets of the San Gabriel Valley and feasting on juicy dumplings on a concrete sea monster, or will you bored and kicking yourself for not getting on the Crime Bus? Read on for all you need to know to avoid that sad fate.<br />&nbsp;<br />For this Saturday, September 29, Esotouric&#8217;s Crime Bus offers a rare edition of its wackiest true crime and history tour, Blood &amp; Dumplings. Tickets for the four-to-five hour luxury coach tour, including dumplings, are $60. Heading due East out of downtown for points rarely seen, the tour explores several historic communities that reflect the growth and eccentricity that are hallmarks of 20th century Los Angeles.</p>
<p>Crime Bus passengers will be treated to detailed descriptions of some of the most notorious, strange and fascinating forgotten tales from the past hundred years, each told at the scene of the crime. They&#8217;ll thrill to the freakish case of the Man from Mars Bandit who stalked area supermarkets for months in 1951 before meeting his match in a police sharpshooter, shock to discover the deadly infighting among El Monte&#8217;s American Nazi Party members, mourn the Case of the Buried Bride dragged beneath her home on her wedding day by her secret lover, gnash teeth at the weird lion farm (home to every MGM lion) that served lion meat barbecues on special occasions, and visit scenes of notorious cases including Phil Spector&#8217;s spooky hilltop castle, James Ellroy&#8217;s murder victim mother Geneva (the true-life inspiration for his Black Dahlia novel), neglected Manson victim Steve Parent and even an obscure East LA link to the JFK assassination.<br />&nbsp;<br />And since no visit to the San Gabriel Valley is complete without a delicious Chinese meal, the Crime Bus will stop at 101 Noodle Express (one of Jonathan Gold&#8217;s picks for 99 L.A. restaurants not to be missed) to pick up a dumpling feast, which will be enjoyed picnic-style at Monster Park, a remarkable sea-themed folk art environment recently saved from demolition. There passengers can enjoy their snack in the mouth of a concrete whale, or under a grinning octopus, then pose for photos with the creatures. </p>
<p>All this, plus stunning mid-century trailer parks, subterranean Black Panther hideouts, wild shootouts, dope-dealing druggists, missing Salvador Dali paintings, the original&nbsp; &quot;little girl down a well&quot; television sensation, and a very strange story about ducks.</p>
<p>This tour is my personal favorite of all our tours, packed with more offbeat history, horror, roadside architecture and fabulous Route 66 vistas than any other. We don&#8217;t offer it very often, and I highly recommend it to anyone who has been thinking about getting on the Crime Bus.</p>
<p>And don&#8217;t forget, we offer 15% discounts for KCRW members, gift certificates, and Season Pass deals ($30 off four tours for one person) that can be applied retroactively for recent passengers. </p>
<p>For more info on Esotouric, or to reserve your seat, visit<br /><a href="https://www.esotouric.com/" target="_blank">https://www.esotouric.com/</a> <br />&nbsp;<br />Upcoming Esotouric bus tour schedule:<br />Sat Sept 29 &ndash; Blood &amp; Dumplings (San Gabriel Valley true crime tour)<br />Sun Oct 7&ndash; Reyner Banham Loves Los Angeles (architecture/urbanism tour)<br />Sat Oct 20&ndash; The Real Black Dahlia tour<br />Sun Oct 21 &ndash; Where the Action Was (rock history tour)<br />Sat Oct 27 &ndash; Haunts of a Dirty Old Man: Charles Bukowski&#8217;s LA<br />Sun Oct 28 &ndash; Hallowe&#8217;en Horrors featuring Crimebo the Clown</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/09/26/saturday-929-explore-the-san-gabriel-valleys-legacy-of-weird-crimes-sea-monsters-and-great-eats/">Saturday 9/29 &#8211; Explore the San Gabriel Valley&#8217;s legacy of weird crimes, sea monsters and great eats</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://1947project.com/2007/09/26/saturday-929-explore-the-san-gabriel-valleys-legacy-of-weird-crimes-sea-monsters-and-great-eats/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Headless Chicken Hitchhikes in Monterey Park!</title>
		<link>https://1947project.com/2007/06/24/headless-chicken-hitchhikes-in-monterey-park/</link>
					<comments>https://1947project.com/2007/06/24/headless-chicken-hitchhikes-in-monterey-park/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joan Renner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2007 19:09:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Joan Renner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monterey park]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san gabriel valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chicken theft]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wacko file]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.1947redux.richardschave.com/2007/06/24/headless-chicken-hitchhikes-in-monterey-park/</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>June 25, 1927Monterey Park The latest version of the old riddle, &#8220;Why did the chicken cross the road&#8221;, debuted today in Judge P.F. Guaiano&#8217;s courtroom. It fell flat. While cruising his regular beat in the hills south of Monterey Park, Officer T.J. Neal eyeballed&#160;some shady looking characters in an automobile. The lawman resolved to have&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://1947project.com/2007/06/24/headless-chicken-hitchhikes-in-monterey-park/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Headless Chicken Hitchhikes in Monterey Park!</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/06/24/headless-chicken-hitchhikes-in-monterey-park/">Headless Chicken Hitchhikes in Monterey Park!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p><img loading="lazy" title="headless chicken headline" height="87" alt="headless chicken headline" src="//farm2.static.flickr.com/1062/614176362_ee6e55d8ca.jpg" width="500" border="0" /></p>
<p>June 25, 1927<br />Monterey Park</p>
<p>The latest version of the old riddle, <a title="Chicken Crosses Road" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Why_did_the_chicken_cross_the_road?" target="_blank">&ldquo;Why did the chicken cross the road&rdquo;</a>, debuted today in Judge P.F. Guaiano&rsquo;s courtroom. It fell flat. </p>
<p>While cruising his regular beat in the hills south of <a title="Monterey Park" href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&#038;hl=en&#038;q=monterey+park,+ca&#038;ie=UTF8&#038;z=13&#038;iwloc=addr&#038;om=1" target="_blank">Monterey Park</a>, Officer T.J. Neal eyeballed&nbsp;some shady looking characters in an automobile. The lawman resolved to have a look, and after further investigation he discovered three men, a decapitated chicken and three empty sacks with feathers stuck to them.&nbsp; Arriving at the obvious conclusion that the poultry had been pinched, Neal demanded an explanation for the beheaded bird. The suspects related a story so improbable it left the cop scratching his head in disbelief. </p>
<p>According to the men, Yeacio Tavary of <a title="Downey" href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&#038;hl=en&#038;q=downey,+ca&#038;ie=UTF8&#038;z=12&#038;iwloc=addr&#038;om=1" target="_blank">Downey</a>, Isa Magana of <a title="Belvedere Gardens" href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&#038;hl=en&#038;q=belvedere+park+los+angeles&#038;sll=37.0625,-95.677071&#038;sspn=34.587666,86.396484&#038;ie=UTF8&#038;ll=34.039165,-118.161864&#038;spn=0.008837,0.021093&#038;z=16&#038;iwloc=addr&#038;om=1" target="_blank">Belvedere</a>, and Daniel Garcia of <a title="Los Angeles" href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&#038;hl=en&#038;q=los+angeles,+ca&#038;ie=UTF8&#038;z=9&#038;iwloc=addr&#038;om=1" target="_blank">Los Angeles</a>, they had been out for a drive when they spied a headless chicken running amok through the countryside. Imagine their surprise when, without warning, the frenzied fowl dashed up to their car and jumped in!</p>
<p>What were they to do? The bird possessed no identification, which ruled out returning it to its rightful owner. After a brief confab, the trio had decided to keep the bird and had been on their way to cook the obliging entree when they were rousted.</p>
<p>Officer Neal hadn&rsquo;t believed the fantastic tale of the hitchhiking chicken, and apparently neither had Judge Guaiano who mused &ldquo;Chickens are not that foolish&rdquo;, and ordered the defendants to spend ten days in the slammer.</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/06/24/headless-chicken-hitchhikes-in-monterey-park/">Headless Chicken Hitchhikes in Monterey Park!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://1947project.com/2007/06/24/headless-chicken-hitchhikes-in-monterey-park/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>AP feature: Crime tours take passengers through LA&#8217;s criminal past</title>
		<link>https://1947project.com/2007/05/07/ap-feature-crime-tours-take-passengers-through-las-criminal-past/</link>
					<comments>https://1947project.com/2007/05/07/ap-feature-crime-tours-take-passengers-through-las-criminal-past/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2007 04:00:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Black Dahlia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crime Bus Tours]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[raymond chandler]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san gabriel valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jacob adelman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>by Jacob Adelman for the Associated Press (AP Photo/Damian Dovarganes) Above: Kelly Kuvo, the Blonde Dahlia &#160; LOS ANGELES &#8212; A dismembered wannabe starlet. A girl buried under her family&#8217;s home. A rattlesnake used as a weapon. The scenes of those crimes are stops on a series of Southern California bus tours that eschew the&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://1947project.com/2007/05/07/ap-feature-crime-tours-take-passengers-through-las-criminal-past/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">AP feature: Crime tours take passengers through LA&#8217;s criminal past</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/05/07/ap-feature-crime-tours-take-passengers-through-las-criminal-past/">AP feature: Crime tours take passengers through LA&#8217;s criminal past</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>by Jacob Adelman for the Associated Press (AP Photo/Damian Dovarganes)</p>
<p><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/richardschave/487586327/" title="Photo Sharing"><img loading="lazy" width="500" height="375" border="0" src="//farm1.static.flickr.com/170/487586327_8fd5644edb.jpg" alt="Kelly at Marlowe's Office Building" /></a></p>
<p align="right"><strong>Above: Kelly Kuvo, the Blonde Dahlia</strong> &nbsp;</p>
<p>LOS ANGELES &#8212; A dismembered wannabe starlet. A girl buried under her family&#8217;s home. A rattlesnake used as a weapon.</p>
<p>The scenes of those crimes are stops on a series of Southern California bus tours that eschew the usual stars&#8217; homes and theme parks to offer passengers a peak at the region&#8217;s dark side.</p>
<p>&quot;They&#8217;re aimed at the history geek sort of people,&quot; said Kelly Kuvo, who wears a black veil and other vintage accouterments during the trips she leads for tour company Esotouric.</p>
<p>The company&#8217;s &quot;crime bus&quot; tours plumb the grisly, blood-soaked pasts of now quiet Southern California neighborhoods and nondescript strip malls.</p>
<p>Similar trips elsewhere take passengers deep into cities&#8217; gory pasts, including Washington&#8217;s &quot;Bad Olde Days&quot; chronicling crime in the nation&#8217;s capital and &quot;Sinister London&quot; that follows the steps of Jack the Ripper.</p>
<p>&quot;When people die in a place, it does change that place forever,&quot; said Esotouric guide and co-founder Kim Cooper. &quot;Just because the people wandering around the neighborhood may not be aware of it, it doesn&#8217;t mean it&#8217;s not a good idea for people who are interested in history to revive those memories.&quot;</p>
<p>John G. Cawelti, who writes about the seductiveness of violent crime tales in his book &quot;Mystery, Violence, and Popular Culture,&quot; said the tours play into people&#8217;s fears of death and catastrophe.</p>
<p>&quot;We live in an age where the worst kinds of things can happen to anybody,&quot; Cawelti said. &quot;Walk down the street and something blows up and all of a sudden you lost your life or lost a leg. The fact that somebody else went through this becomes a surrogate &ndash; a magical way of charming away the fear of the possibility.&quot;</p>
<p>Esotouric&#8217;s most popular tour explores 1947 Los Angeles by zeroing in on the murder of Elizabeth Short &ndash; a.k.a. &quot;Black Dahlia&quot; &ndash; who came to Hollywood in search of fame but wound up the victim of an infamous unsolved murder.</p>
<p>One stop is a ground-floor storefront on a desolate downtown street that now boasts a sign reading, &quot;Club Galaxy &ndash; 100 Beautiful Girls.&quot;</p>
<p>In 1947, when it was a bistro called &quot;The Crown Grill,&quot; it was the last place Short was seen before her dismembered body was discovered miles away in a south Los Angeles neighborhood.</p>
<p>&quot;She was friendly with the bartenders and with some of the waitresses, so people recognized her and remembered her,&quot; Cooper said. &quot;The problem of course is that everybody at the Crown Grill immediately became suspects.&quot;</p>
<p>Passengers are also introduced to lesser known crimes from the same year, such as the attempted carjacking in Hollywood of an 18-year-old movie theater cashier named Ginevra Knight, who shot her assailant dead.</p>
<p>&quot;It&#8217;s the criminal history of 1947 L.A. and how women felt going out at night in the hysteria of an unsolved murder,&quot; Cooper said.</p>
<p>The &quot;Blood and Dumplings&quot; tour through San Gabriel Valley suburbs, meanwhile, passes the home where a young bride-to-be was buried in 1969 by her uncle after he shot her to death in a jealous rage at the end of their affair.</p>
<p>It also cruises by an intersection where a man named Raymond James bought a rattlesnake he let bite his wife in 1935 so he could cash in on her insurance policy. When she didn&#8217;t die, he had an accomplice finish the job by drowning her in their fish pond.</p>
<p>Esotouric grew out of a Web log Cooper started in 2005, when she set out to retell a true-crime tale from each day of 1947. She and her collaborators soon started offering tours of those scenes and the sites of other crimes.</p>
<p>A tour that revisits the life and literature of Raymond Chandler, whose fictional characters inhabit the region&#8217;s underworld, was added to the menu of crime junkets when the company was started earlier this year.</p>
<p>Tour participant Bob Nickum, 59, a school district business manager, said seeing the sites of past crimes made him look at familiar places in a new way.</p>
<p>&quot;It&#8217;s just very interesting to drive around the area and to see things I may have passed by many times and maybe not known what happened there,&quot; said Nickum, who, like most passengers, lives in Southern California.</p>
<p>&quot;It makes things a little more interesting &ndash; vivid &ndash; to know about something that intense that took place in a calm, peaceful neighborhood,&quot; he said.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a title="Photo Sharing" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/richardschave/487557160/"><img loading="lazy" width="500" height="375" border="0" alt="Nathan Heather and Kelly" src="//farm1.static.flickr.com/168/487557160_02588d149e.jpg" /></a></p>
<p align="right"><strong>Nathan Marsak, chess shark Heather and Kelly at the Hotel Barclay<br /></strong></p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/05/07/ap-feature-crime-tours-take-passengers-through-las-criminal-past/">AP feature: Crime tours take passengers through LA&#8217;s criminal past</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://1947project.com/2007/05/07/ap-feature-crime-tours-take-passengers-through-las-criminal-past/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blood &#038; Dumplings Crime Bus Podcast</title>
		<link>https://1947project.com/2007/03/28/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-podcast/</link>
					<comments>https://1947project.com/2007/03/28/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-podcast/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2007 06:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crime Bus Tours]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san gabriel valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Gabriel Valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jacob adelman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lana clarkson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phil spector]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jacob Adelman of the venerable AP rode along with the gang on the Blood &#38; Dumplings Crime Bus Tour on St. Patrick&#8217;s Day, and produced a delightful little audio document of the day for the AP&#8217;s youth-oriented asap section. It includes an overview of the tour, some excerpted crime stories from the tour, and interviews&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://1947project.com/2007/03/28/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-podcast/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Blood &#038; Dumplings Crime Bus Podcast</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/03/28/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-podcast/">Blood &#038; Dumplings Crime Bus Podcast</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>Jacob Adelman of the venerable AP rode along with the gang on the Blood &amp; Dumplings Crime Bus Tour on St. Patrick&#8217;s Day, and produced a delightful little audio document of the day for the AP&#8217;s youth-oriented asap section. It includes an overview of the tour, some excerpted crime stories from the tour, and interviews with a few of the delightful passengers. Why would otherwise normal people choose to spend their Saturday hearing tales of mayhem and horror? <a href="https://asap.ap.org/stories/1330755.s" target="_blank">Click slowly</a> and see&#8230;.</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/03/28/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-podcast/">Blood &#038; Dumplings Crime Bus Podcast</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://1947project.com/2007/03/28/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-podcast/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blood &#038; Dumplings in the Pasadena Star-News</title>
		<link>https://1947project.com/2007/03/19/blood-dumplings-in-the-pasadena-star-news/</link>
					<comments>https://1947project.com/2007/03/19/blood-dumplings-in-the-pasadena-star-news/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2007 02:23:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crime Bus Tours]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[El Monte]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nathan marsak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san gabriel valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Gabriel Valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blood and dumplings]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[crime bus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pasadena star-news]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Why yes, Pasadenans, that was our own Nathan Marsak glowering out at you from page three of the Sunday paper, doing his little AH impression on the former site of the American Nazi Party Headquarters in deepest El Monte, as part of the Blood and Dumplings Crime Bus Tour. To read Molly R. Okean&#8217;s story,&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://1947project.com/2007/03/19/blood-dumplings-in-the-pasadena-star-news/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Blood &#038; Dumplings in the Pasadena Star-News</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/03/19/blood-dumplings-in-the-pasadena-star-news/">Blood &#038; Dumplings in the Pasadena Star-News</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div><a title="Photo Sharing" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/richardschave/426125566/"><img loading="lazy" width="458" height="500" border="0" alt="Nathan Marsak as Hitler on the 1947project Crime Bus Tour" src="//farm1.static.flickr.com/153/426125566_e00cd048c1.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Why yes, Pasadenans, that <em>was</em> our own Nathan Marsak glowering out at you from page three of the Sunday paper, doing his little AH impression on the former site of the American Nazi Party Headquarters in deepest El Monte, as part of the Blood and Dumplings Crime Bus Tour. To read Molly R. Okean&#8217;s story, which oddly enough in the web version doesn&#8217;t feature Sarah Reingewirtz&#8217; striking photograph, just <a href="https://www.pasadenastarnews.com/news/ci_5464230" target="_blank">click here</a>.</p>
<p>We had a great day exploring the San Gabriel Valley with a bus full of charming passengers, including a stop for dumplings at Monster Park (sorry about the soy sauce shortage!), turn-of-the-century bungalow poetry from co-host Richard Schave, black cats crossing our paths and some truly chilling tales of forgotten crimes and misfortunes. Thanks to everyone who joined us, especially Sister Kelly and Brother Nathan, and watch this space for announcements of upcoming tours, criminal and otherwise.&nbsp;</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/03/19/blood-dumplings-in-the-pasadena-star-news/">Blood &#038; Dumplings in the Pasadena Star-News</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://1947project.com/2007/03/19/blood-dumplings-in-the-pasadena-star-news/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blood &#038; Dumplings Crime Bus Tour (March 17, 1pm-6pm)</title>
		<link>https://1947project.com/2007/02/24/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-tour-march-17-1pm-6pm/</link>
					<comments>https://1947project.com/2007/02/24/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-tour-march-17-1pm-6pm/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2007 04:22:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crime Bus Tours]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[El Monte]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monterey park]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san gabriel valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Gabriel Valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alhambra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manson family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phil spector]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If there&#8217;s one thing we at 1947project love even more than uncovering evidence of an incredibly weird forgotten crime, it&#8217;s Chinese food&#8211;especially dumplings! Whether fried or boiled, stuffed with shrimp, pork, pumpkin, fish, scallions or sometimes a little dollop of soup, nothing is more comforting and delicious. With Blood &#38; Dumplings, we&#8217;re combining our favorite&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://1947project.com/2007/02/24/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-tour-march-17-1pm-6pm/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Blood &#038; Dumplings Crime Bus Tour (March 17, 1pm-6pm)</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/02/24/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-tour-march-17-1pm-6pm/">Blood &#038; Dumplings Crime Bus Tour (March 17, 1pm-6pm)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p>If there&#8217;s one thing we at 1947project love even more than uncovering<br />  evidence of an incredibly weird forgotten crime, it&#8217;s Chinese<br />  food&#8211;especially dumplings! Whether fried or boiled, stuffed with<br />  shrimp, pork, pumpkin, fish, scallions or sometimes a little dollop of<br />  soup, nothing is more comforting and delicious.</p>
<p>  With <strong>Blood &amp; Dumplings</strong>, we&#8217;re combining our favorite things to bring<br />  you the first new Crime Bus tour of 2007, a a grim and gleeful descent<br />  into the criminal history of the San Gabriel Valley, including the battling Nazis of El Monte, the chilling (and probably incestuous) Case of the Buried Bride, missing Salvador Dali paintings, the dark history of the Lions Club&#8217;s lion meat BBQs held in eye- and nose-range of hundreds of the lovely beasts, the Man from Mars Bandit (his mystery revealed!), plus Phil Spector, neglected Manson victim Steve Parent, Geneva Ellroy and a peculiar East L.A. link to the JFK assassination, concealed Black Panthers and the coolest trailer parks in the Southland.</p>
<p>Included in the $55 ticket price is a special stop for Chinese comfort food at one of the best dumpling joints in Monterey Park&nbsp; and an afternoon picnic surrounded by real sea monsters.</p>
<p>  Click <a href="https://crimebus.dumplingjoint.com/" target="_blank">here</a> to buy your ticket by paypal, or <a href="https://www.47upgradepath7.richardschave.com//feedback" target="_self">email</a> to reserve a seat that you will purchase with a money order or check.</p>
<p>We hope to see YOU on the Crime Bus!</p>
<p>your hosts,<br />Kim Cooper &amp; Richard Schave </p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/02/24/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-tour-march-17-1pm-6pm/">Blood &#038; Dumplings Crime Bus Tour (March 17, 1pm-6pm)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://1947project.com/2007/02/24/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-tour-march-17-1pm-6pm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
