<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="https://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="https://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>birthday &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/birthday-2/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Los Angeles De-Mythified</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 19:49:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-1947logoSquare-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>birthday &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Book Crimebo For Your Event</title>
		<link>/2006/08/09/book-crimebo-for-your-event/</link>
					<comments>/2006/08/09/book-crimebo-for-your-event/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2006 19:27:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crimebo the Clown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[los angeles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weird]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[anniversary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bachelor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bachelorette]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clowns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[party]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Crimebo the Crime Clown is regularly available for party and event bookings within the metro Los Angeles area, and phone greetings anywhere. Out of town trips and other unusual requests can sometimes be accomodated, so please ask. For more info, visit his page at Esotouric. Interested? Contact us with any questions, or to ask if &#8230; <a href="/2006/08/09/book-crimebo-for-your-event/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Book Crimebo For Your Event</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2006/08/09/book-crimebo-for-your-event/">Book Crimebo For Your Event</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p>Crimebo the Crime Clown is regularly available for party and event bookings within the metro Los Angeles area, and phone greetings anywhere. Out of town trips and other unusual requests can sometimes be accomodated, so please ask. For more info, visit <a href="https://www.esotouric.com/crimebo" target="_blank">his page</a> at Esotouric.</p>
<p>Interested? <a target="_blank" href="https://www.47upgradepath7.richardschave.com//feedback">Contact us</a> with any questions, or to ask if your desired date and time are available. If you want the personalized touch, please include dates of the honoree&#8217;s birthday or anniversary (if different from the event date), so Crimebo can research all the terrible things that happened on that date. </p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2006/08/09/book-crimebo-for-your-event/">Book Crimebo For Your Event</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/08/09/book-crimebo-for-your-event/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Introducing Crimebo, the 1947project Crime Clown</title>
		<link>/2006/07/27/introducing-crimebo-the-1947project-crime-clown/</link>
					<comments>/2006/07/27/introducing-crimebo-the-1947project-crime-clown/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2006 03:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crime Bus Tours]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crimebo the Clown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The wacko file]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[birthday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[clown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[michael perrick]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[parties]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shower]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Press release July 26, 2006 Crimebo the 1947project Crime Clown Brings Morbid Fun To Special Events in L.A. LOS ANGELES- Afterwards, the guests had to admit the party had been dragging a little, when Crimebo the Crime Clown pulled up in his windowless murder van (with the passenger side doors disabled) and emerged clutching his &#8230; <a href="/2006/07/27/introducing-crimebo-the-1947project-crime-clown/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Introducing Crimebo, the 1947project Crime Clown</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2006/07/27/introducing-crimebo-the-1947project-crime-clown/">Introducing Crimebo, the 1947project Crime Clown</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>Press release</p>
<p> July 26, 2006</p>
<p> Crimebo the 1947project Crime Clown Brings Morbid Fun To Special Events in L.A.</p>
<p> LOS ANGELES- Afterwards, the guests had to admit the party had been dragging a little, when Crimebo the Crime Clown pulled up in his windowless murder van (with the passenger side doors disabled) and emerged clutching his Big Book of Terrible Crimes. With a hearty &quot;Hiya Mr. Birthday Boy, wanna learn something bad about your special day?,&quot; Crimebo launched into a hilariously disturbing litany of murders, kidnapping, arsons and high weirdness, winding up with the declaration that only someone pretty twisted would have the foresight to be born on a day like that, handing out some Crimebo Fan Club Cards and racing off into the night &quot;to do bad stuff.&quot; </p>
<p> Crimebo the Crime Clown is not your ordinary party entertainer. Armed with his Big Book of Terrible Crimes, this witty and sinister fellow brings to every birthday party, wedding shower or office bash a window into an alternate, ultra-creepy history.</p>
<p> Was someone kidnapped, murdered or tarred and feathered on your special day? Do you share a birthday with a serial killer? Is your wedding day also the anniversary of a notable execution? Crimebo the Crime Clown has the skinny, and he&#8217;ll share it with his unique brand of morbid glee.</p>
<p> If you&#8217;re truly twisted, or love someone who is, then Crimebo is the perfect addition to your next celebration. With research provided by the acclaimed true crime bloggers of the 1947project, Crimebo knows when all the famous bodies were buried, but also about the utterly strange, forgotten happenings that are calibrated to blow minds.</p>
<p> Crimebo will be making a special public appearance on the next 1947project Pasadena Confidential Crime Bus Tour on August 6, and is available with one week&#8217;s notice to appear at events throughout the Los Angeles area. A personal visit from Crimebo costs $150. Telephone greetings are also available.</p>
<p> Crimebo is currently portrayed by Michael Perrick, host and creator of the popular Jew Night celebrations at Mr. T&#8217;s Bowl and otherwise known as Fucko the Clown.</p>
<p> To schedule an interview with Crimebo or 1947project blogger Kim Cooper, contact Kim at amscray@gmail.com, 323-223-2767</p>
<p> For more info on the 1947project blog or Pasadena Confidential Crime Bus tour, visit /</p>
<p></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2006/07/27/introducing-crimebo-the-1947project-crime-clown/">Introducing Crimebo, the 1947project Crime Clown</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/07/27/introducing-crimebo-the-1947project-crime-clown/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
