<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="https://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="https://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>hanging &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/execution-3/hanging-2/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Los Angeles De-Mythified</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 21:34:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-1947logoSquare-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>hanging &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>All for Love</title>
		<link>/2007/05/30/all-for-love/</link>
					<comments>/2007/05/30/all-for-love/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2007 17:40:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Downtown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hanging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mary McCoy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Murder]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Strangulation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Suicide]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>May 30, 1927&#160; The troubled love affair between New York showgirl Evelyn Tatum and her estranged husband, artist Lawrence Mueller came to a violent end this morning at the Rosegrove Hotel at 532 S. Flower St.&#160; Reunited for &#34;one last week of happiness&#34; before separating, Mueller strangled his bride while &#34;All for Love&#34; played on &#8230; <a href="/2007/05/30/all-for-love/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">All for Love</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2007/05/30/all-for-love/">All for Love</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p>May 30, 1927&nbsp;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" width="209" height="240" border="0" align="left" src="//farm1.static.flickr.com/204/511141958_501f0b5243_m.jpg" alt="murdersuicide" title="murdersuicide" />The troubled love affair between New York showgirl Evelyn Tatum and her estranged husband, artist Lawrence Mueller came to a violent end this morning at the Rosegrove Hotel at <a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&#038;hl=en&#038;q=532+s.+flower+st.,+los+angeles,+ca&#038;sll=37.0625,-95.677068&#038;sspn=29.358024,59.765625&#038;ie=UTF8&#038;ll=34.052642,-118.256536&#038;spn=0.007485,0.014591&#038;z=16&#038;om=1" target="_blank">532 S. Flower St</a>.&nbsp; Reunited for &quot;one last week of happiness&quot; before separating, Mueller strangled his bride while &quot;All for Love&quot; played on the phonograph, then hung himself with the hotel bedspread.&nbsp; The events leading up to the tragedy were revealed through the stack of correspondence found alongside their bodies in the hotel room.<img loading="lazy" width="230" height="240" border="0" align="right" src="//farm1.static.flickr.com/202/521798252_f51e53f936_m.jpg" alt="rosegrovehotel" title="rosegrovehotel" /></p>
<p>The couple met in Denver, quickly wed, and moved to El Centro where Mueller was employed as an artist for a sign company.&nbsp; Tatum found life in El Centro stifling, and left Mueller for Los Angeles after two months of married life.&nbsp; She was immediately cast as the lead in a Shelly Players Theater in Huntington Park, and was set to begin work ten days later.&nbsp; Upon hearing Tatum&#8217;s news, Mueller sent a wire addressed to &quot;My Golden Girl&quot; that read, &quot;Received you wire and at first I rejoiced with you.&nbsp; It seemed that the solution to all our troubles was found and that at last we could be happy together.&quot;<br /><img loading="lazy" width="75" height="240" border="0" align="left" src="//farm1.static.flickr.com/222/511141952_0495f73a14_m.jpg" alt="evelynmueller" title="evelynmueller" /><br />However, Mueller began to overanalyze the situation, and concluded that since he would work days, and she nights, it was only a matter of time before another man seduced her.&nbsp; &quot;The first one that did, there would be another murder,&quot; he concluded, and wired that it would be best to &quot;take myself out of the picture.&quot;</p>
<p>Tatum apparently agreed wholeheartedly, writing back: &quot;It is best you forget the past two months and me.&nbsp; Go alone to Chicago.&nbsp; Have new friends and work.&nbsp; We both realize for the present we cannot have happiness together.&nbsp; We tried and I alone failed&#8230; Sorry.&quot;&nbsp; Upon receiving this missive, the passionate Mueller raced to Los Angeles where he and Tatum were briefly reunited.&nbsp; However, when it became clear that a reconciliation was not in the cards, Mueller killed her.</p>
<p>The hotel maid found Tatum sprawled across the bed in a filmy pink nightgown, and Mueller&#8217;s nude body hanging from the closet door lintel.&nbsp; Their parents later claimed the bodies.</p>
<div align="left"> </div>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2007/05/30/all-for-love/">All for Love</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2007/05/30/all-for-love/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Eye of a Needle</title>
		<link>/2006/05/02/eye-of-a-needle/</link>
					<comments>/2006/05/02/eye-of-a-needle/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathan Marsak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2006 08:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[hanging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nathan marsak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Suicide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[barn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Russel C. Carter]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>May 2, 1907 Los Angeles Wealthy real estate mogul Russel C. Carter, 939 Denver Avenue, was at 74 in the winter of his years, though comfortably retired. Despite his vast holdings he brooded over ailments real and imagined and obsessed over the idea he would become helpless, an issue he confided only to his son, &#8230; <a href="/2006/05/02/eye-of-a-needle/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Eye of a Needle</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2006/05/02/eye-of-a-needle/">Eye of a Needle</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>May 2, 1907<br />
Los Angeles  </p>
<p>Wealthy real estate mogul Russel C. Carter, 939 Denver Avenue, was at 74 in the winter of his years, though comfortably retired.  Despite his vast holdings he brooded over ailments real and imagined and obsessed over the idea he would become helpless, an issue he confided only to his son, Spring Street haberdasher Norman Carter.  </p>
<p>So, when his wife left the house to-day to go about her day&rsquo;s business, R. C. barricaded himself in the barn, secured a rope to both a beam and his neck, and leaped off a stairway.  When Mrs. Carter returned at 6:30, the patriarch nowhere to be found, neighbors were enlisted to break down the barn door, where she found her husband still swinging.  </p>
<p>She was prostrated with grief and is now under the care of physicians at son Norman&rsquo;s home at 3616 Flower Street.  </p>
<p>While there is much to say about the moneyed class and their admirable relationship to self-determination, this writer merely wishes to send his condolences to the family of an Angeleno with vision.</p></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/2006/05/02/eye-of-a-needle/">Eye of a Needle</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/05/02/eye-of-a-needle/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
