<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="https://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="https://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>exile &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/exile/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Los Angeles De-Mythified</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 19:40:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-1947logoSquare-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>exile &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Exit of a Thirsty Man</title>
		<link>/2007/07/26/exit-of-a-thirsty-man/</link>
					<comments>/2007/07/26/exit-of-a-thirsty-man/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jul 2007 22:31:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[alcohol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beverly Hills]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Victimless crimes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[beverly hills]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[law]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[July 26, 1927Beverly Hills&#160; Architect Fred W. Maack was well prepared when he appeared before City Recorder/ Judge Seth Strelinger to answer to a charge of drunkeness and disorderly conduct. He was willing, he read from a most unusual statement, to voluntarily exile himself for a period of four years from the municipality of Beverly &#8230; <a href="/2007/07/26/exit-of-a-thirsty-man/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Exit of a Thirsty Man</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p>July 26, 1927<br />Beverly Hills&nbsp;</p>
<p>Architect Fred W. Maack was well prepared when he appeared before City Recorder/ Judge Seth Strelinger to answer to a charge of drunkeness and disorderly conduct. He was willing, he read from a most unusual statement, to voluntarily exile himself for a period of four years from the municipality of Beverly Hills (unless granted permission to enter by the BHPD), during which time he would not partake of any intoxicating liquors. Further, he was under the care of a psychiatrist, and would remain so until the doctor deemed him sane.</p>
<p>&quot;In consideration of the above,&quot; Maack read, &quot;I beg to request that I be given a suspended sentence and be permitted to forfeit my bail and that the medical staff of the Beverly Hills Health Department abstain from interfering with my case on the grounds that they are acquainted with the worst phases of my character only&#8211;&quot; (and here the statement deteriorates somewhat into possibly pixilated confusion) &quot;&#8211;and will unintentionally be acting for the good of my family than for my own good and will not be here to bother my family in the future. This is not meant as a criticism, but voices my honest desire to start over, quit drinking and get to work in another community. I have a job waiting for me and if all official record of my being under observation is omitted I will be highly appreciative of the fact.&quot;</p>
<p>Judge Strelinger was impressed by Maack&#8217;s plea, and not only granted the suspended sentence, but ruled that his $100 bail be returned. Here&#8217;s hoping the gentleman stayed dry and built some fine structures, wherever he next settled. </p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2007/07/26/exit-of-a-thirsty-man/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
