<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="https://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="https://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Cons &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<atom:link href="https://1947project.com/tag/cons-17/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://1947project.com/</link>
	<description>Los Angeles De-Mythified</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 21:59:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://1947project.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-1947logoSquare-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>Cons &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<link>https://1947project.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Wanderlust At Sea</title>
		<link>https://1947project.com/2007/10/07/wanderlust-at-sea/</link>
					<comments>https://1947project.com/2007/10/07/wanderlust-at-sea/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathan Marsak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2007 00:19:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Drowning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Embezzlement]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[long beach]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nathan marsak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Riverside]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Seattle]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The wacko file]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[amnesia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cons]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>October 7, 1927Long Beach Between Christ&#8217;s wanderings in the deserts of Jericho, and Kidder&#8217;s huddlings in the gardens of Glendale, there was Robert Sankey. &#160; Sankey, 44, a prominent Riverside contractor, was in a splendid mood September seventh last; he had no domestic or financial troubles, and bid his lovely wife and 13 year-old daughter&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://1947project.com/2007/10/07/wanderlust-at-sea/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Wanderlust At Sea</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/10/07/wanderlust-at-sea/">Wanderlust At Sea</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p><img loading="lazy" width="255" height="270" border="0" align="right" title="manfound!" alt="manfound!" src="//farm3.static.flickr.com/2165/1494760436_705b15e89c_o.jpg" />October 7, 1927<br />Long Beach</p>
<p>Between Christ&rsquo;s wanderings in the deserts of Jericho, and Kidder&rsquo;s huddlings in the gardens of Glendale, there was Robert Sankey. &nbsp;</p>
<p>Sankey, 44, a prominent Riverside contractor, was in a splendid mood September seventh last; he had no domestic or financial troubles, and bid his lovely wife and 13 year-old daughter goodbye that morning in his home at <a title="houseofsankey" target="_blank" href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&#038;hl=en&#038;geocode=&#038;time=&#038;date=&#038;ttype=&#038;q=270+Bandini+Avenue,+Riverside,+California&#038;sll=33.969986,-117.392092&#038;sspn=0.016016,0.029182&#038;ie=UTF8&#038;ll=33.972122,-117.392092&#038;spn=0.032031,0.058365&#038;z=14&#038;iwloc=cent&#038;om=1">270 Bandini Avenue</a> before a trip to Laguna Beach.&nbsp; He made it to Laguna Beach, and picked up $12,000 ($132,359 USD2006) in cash which he had been paid by the Colton School Board for the construction of Colton High School.</p>
<p>Sankey then told friends he was going for a swim, and left his bag, clothing, glasses and&nbsp; shoes at a hotel near the beach.&nbsp; From there he disappeared&hellip;the sea was dragged repeatedly for his body, but to no avail.&nbsp; Had the briny deep swallowed Sankey?&nbsp; And what became of the <em>money</em>?&nbsp; And what&rsquo;s this?&mdash;a few days ago, some Sankey acquaintance came forth and reported having seen Sankey on a Seattle-bound boat a day or two after the disappearance.</p>
<p>Today, Mrs. Paul McKenzie peered nervously through the window of her home at <a title="sankeyssis" target="_blank" href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&#038;hl=en&#038;time=&#038;date=&#038;ttype=&#038;q=4010+E+Massachusetts+St,+Long+Beach,+Los+Angeles,+California+90814,+United+States&#038;sll=33.972122,-117.392092&#038;sspn=0.032031,0.058365&#038;ie=UTF8&#038;cd=1&#038;geocode=0,33.768953,-118.145514&#038;ll=33.76973,-118.145514&#038;spn=0.008027,0.014591&#038;z=16&#038;iwloc=addr&#038;om=1">4010 Massachusetts, Long Beach</a>.&nbsp; There was a dazed, raggedy man wandering aimlessly up and down in front of her house for the better part of two hours.&nbsp; When she got up the nerve to confront the torn and tattered stranger, all a-jibber-jabberin&#8217; to himself, it was, you guessed it, her brother, Robert Sankey.&nbsp; Oh no, he insisted, <em>I&rsquo;m Andrew Borg</em>.</p>
<p>Well, the Borg, I mean Sankey, had only $500 left (in checks issued by a Seattle bank) of the twelve grand, and even less of an idea as to where he&rsquo;d been or what he&rsquo;d done.&nbsp; He could only confirm that his clothes had been given to him by &ldquo;the skipper,&rdquo; and that he&rsquo;d been to sea in a small boat with two men and a woman.</p>
<p>Further investigation revealed that Sankey recently boarded the steamer <a title="theevanger" target="_blank" href="https://content.lib.washington.edu/cdm4/item_viewer.php?CISOROOT=/imlsmaritime&#038;CISOPTR=324&#038;REC=6">Evanger</a> at San Francisco (booking passage to Buenos Aires as &ldquo;Andrew Borg, grain dealer, Witchita, Kan.&rdquo;), but put ashore at San Pedro the day he reappeared in Long Beach.</p>
<p>Sankey remains in his Borgian state at Seaside hospital, where Riverside county authorities are vexed with Seaside staff; the Sheriff is itching to serve two warrants on Sankey, each charging sixteen counts of violating the State wage law, but the pesky physicians demand that officers wait &lsquo;til Sankey&rsquo;s physical condition permits such activity.</p>
<p>Whether amnesia or grift, please bear in mind&hellip;steer clear of small boats, and beware &quot;the skipper.&quot;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" width="236" height="300" border="0" title="theskipper!" alt="theskipper!" src="//farm3.static.flickr.com/2404/1498139467_c6c21d7c86_o.jpg" />&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/10/07/wanderlust-at-sea/">Wanderlust At Sea</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://1947project.com/2007/10/07/wanderlust-at-sea/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Can You Hear Me Now?</title>
		<link>https://1947project.com/2007/06/18/can-you-hear-me-now/</link>
					<comments>https://1947project.com/2007/06/18/can-you-hear-me-now/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Joan Renner]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2007 17:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Downtown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Fraud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Houdini]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joan Renner]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spiritualism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The wacko file]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cons]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>June 18, 1927 Los Angeles Egyptian mystic Hamid Bey claims to have received a message from deceased illusionist Harry Houdini &#8211; but Hardeen, Houdini&#8217;s surviving brother, doesn&#8217;t believe that Bey&#8217;s claim is any more genuine than many others made since the magician&#8217;s death last Halloween. Hardeen would love to hear from his brother Harry, and&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://1947project.com/2007/06/18/can-you-hear-me-now/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Can You Hear Me Now?</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/06/18/can-you-hear-me-now/">Can You Hear Me Now?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p><img loading="lazy" width="238" height="209" border="0" src="//farm2.static.flickr.com/1141/561906273_d774cc55de_o.jpg" alt="Houdini Headline" title="Houdini Headline" /></p>
<p>June 18, 1927 <br />Los Angeles</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" width="159" height="231" border="0" align="right" src="//farm2.static.flickr.com/1024/561906269_5157e02ffc_m.jpg" alt="Hamid Bey" title="Hamid Bey" />Egyptian mystic Hamid Bey claims to have received a message from deceased illusionist <a target="_blank" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Houdini" title="Harry Houdini">Harry Houdini</a> &ndash; but Hardeen, Houdini&rsquo;s surviving brother, doesn&rsquo;t believe that Bey&rsquo;s claim is any more genuine than many others made since the magician&rsquo;s death last Halloween. </p>
<p>Hardeen would love to hear from his brother Harry, and has offered $10,000 ($119,510.92 USD 2007) to anyone who can name only one or two words of a secret code which he devised with Houdini, and another deceased brother, William. The brothers entered into the pact prior to William&rsquo;s death last year in order to prove that the dead cannot communicate with the living. They agreed that the code would be the preamble to any communication from beyond the grave. Hardeen said that he and Houdini never heard from William following his death. </p>
<p>Bey has spent most of this year on the <a target="_blank" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vaudeville" title="Vaudeville">vaudeville</a> circuit performing feats such as being buried alive and then revived. Mr. Bey asserts his powers are divine gifts, and he had intended to challenge Houdini&rsquo;s well documented skepticism of spiritualists. Throughout his life Houdini had scorned spiritualists and had often stated that he could duplicate, by mechanical means, any of the stunts performed by a medium. Unfortunately Houdini died before the two could meet. </p>
<p>Prior to his current stint in vaudeville, Bey spent a few years traveling around the world publicly demonstrating powers had he learned at a <a target="_blank" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Coptics" title="Copts">Coptic</a> Temple in Egypt. While in Brindisi, Italy, he had a near death experience. He had announced that he was going to induce a state of <a target="_blank" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Suspended_animation" title="suspended animation">suspended animation</a>, and allow himself to be buried alive for three days. His plan to fast prior to his entombment was foiled by the residents of <a target="_blank" href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&#038;hl=en&#038;q=Brindisi,+Italy&#038;ie=UTF8&#038;ll=40.81173,17.759399&#038;spn=0.972867,2.69989&#038;z=9&#038;iwloc=addr&#038;om=1" title="Brindisi, Italy">Brindisi</a> when they prepared a sumptuous banquet in his honor, and pressed him to eat several large plates of spaghetti. </p>
<p>When he awakened from his trance he was buried and unable to breathe &ndash; he then pulled the emergency cord which rang a bell above ground to summon help to his gravesite. Bey later stated that his trance had been disrupted by the spaghetti he had consumed. </p>
<p>Were cosmic forces responsible for interrupting Hamid&rsquo;s trance, or were a bad case of indigestion and a subconscious desire not to remain buried under six feet of Italian soil the reasons for his premature resurrection? It is a shame that fate intervened and denied us the outcome of a confrontation between Hamid Bey and Harry Houdini. </p>
<p>Houdini&rsquo;s wife Bess held a s&eacute;ance on Halloween every year through 1936 when she declared that &ldquo;ten years is long enough to wait for any man.&rdquo; No authentic message from Houdini has ever been received. </p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/06/18/can-you-hear-me-now/">Can You Hear Me Now?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://1947project.com/2007/06/18/can-you-hear-me-now/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
