<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="https://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="https://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>phil spector &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<atom:link href="https://1947project.com/tag/phil-spector-3/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://1947project.com/</link>
	<description>Los Angeles De-Mythified</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 19:47:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://1947project.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-1947logoSquare-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>phil spector &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<link>https://1947project.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Saturday 9/29 &#8211; Explore the San Gabriel Valley&#8217;s legacy of weird crimes, sea monsters and great eats</title>
		<link>https://1947project.com/2007/09/26/saturday-929-explore-the-san-gabriel-valleys-legacy-of-weird-crimes-sea-monsters-and-great-eats/</link>
					<comments>https://1947project.com/2007/09/26/saturday-929-explore-the-san-gabriel-valleys-legacy-of-weird-crimes-sea-monsters-and-great-eats/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2007 13:41:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crime Bus Tours]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[james ellroy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nazis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san gabriel valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Gabriel Valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phil spector]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Gentle reader, What are you doing Saturday afternoon? Will you be among the lucky citizens exploring the strange secrets of the San Gabriel Valley and feasting on juicy dumplings on a concrete sea monster, or will you bored and kicking yourself for not getting on the Crime Bus? Read on for all you need to&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://1947project.com/2007/09/26/saturday-929-explore-the-san-gabriel-valleys-legacy-of-weird-crimes-sea-monsters-and-great-eats/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Saturday 9/29 &#8211; Explore the San Gabriel Valley&#8217;s legacy of weird crimes, sea monsters and great eats</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/09/26/saturday-929-explore-the-san-gabriel-valleys-legacy-of-weird-crimes-sea-monsters-and-great-eats/">Saturday 9/29 &#8211; Explore the San Gabriel Valley&#8217;s legacy of weird crimes, sea monsters and great eats</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p>Gentle reader,</p>
<p>What are you doing Saturday afternoon? Will you be among the lucky citizens exploring the strange secrets of the San Gabriel Valley and feasting on juicy dumplings on a concrete sea monster, or will you bored and kicking yourself for not getting on the Crime Bus? Read on for all you need to know to avoid that sad fate.<br />&nbsp;<br />For this Saturday, September 29, Esotouric&#8217;s Crime Bus offers a rare edition of its wackiest true crime and history tour, Blood &amp; Dumplings. Tickets for the four-to-five hour luxury coach tour, including dumplings, are $60. Heading due East out of downtown for points rarely seen, the tour explores several historic communities that reflect the growth and eccentricity that are hallmarks of 20th century Los Angeles.</p>
<p>Crime Bus passengers will be treated to detailed descriptions of some of the most notorious, strange and fascinating forgotten tales from the past hundred years, each told at the scene of the crime. They&#8217;ll thrill to the freakish case of the Man from Mars Bandit who stalked area supermarkets for months in 1951 before meeting his match in a police sharpshooter, shock to discover the deadly infighting among El Monte&#8217;s American Nazi Party members, mourn the Case of the Buried Bride dragged beneath her home on her wedding day by her secret lover, gnash teeth at the weird lion farm (home to every MGM lion) that served lion meat barbecues on special occasions, and visit scenes of notorious cases including Phil Spector&#8217;s spooky hilltop castle, James Ellroy&#8217;s murder victim mother Geneva (the true-life inspiration for his Black Dahlia novel), neglected Manson victim Steve Parent and even an obscure East LA link to the JFK assassination.<br />&nbsp;<br />And since no visit to the San Gabriel Valley is complete without a delicious Chinese meal, the Crime Bus will stop at 101 Noodle Express (one of Jonathan Gold&#8217;s picks for 99 L.A. restaurants not to be missed) to pick up a dumpling feast, which will be enjoyed picnic-style at Monster Park, a remarkable sea-themed folk art environment recently saved from demolition. There passengers can enjoy their snack in the mouth of a concrete whale, or under a grinning octopus, then pose for photos with the creatures. </p>
<p>All this, plus stunning mid-century trailer parks, subterranean Black Panther hideouts, wild shootouts, dope-dealing druggists, missing Salvador Dali paintings, the original&nbsp; &quot;little girl down a well&quot; television sensation, and a very strange story about ducks.</p>
<p>This tour is my personal favorite of all our tours, packed with more offbeat history, horror, roadside architecture and fabulous Route 66 vistas than any other. We don&#8217;t offer it very often, and I highly recommend it to anyone who has been thinking about getting on the Crime Bus.</p>
<p>And don&#8217;t forget, we offer 15% discounts for KCRW members, gift certificates, and Season Pass deals ($30 off four tours for one person) that can be applied retroactively for recent passengers. </p>
<p>For more info on Esotouric, or to reserve your seat, visit<br /><a href="https://www.esotouric.com/" target="_blank">https://www.esotouric.com/</a> <br />&nbsp;<br />Upcoming Esotouric bus tour schedule:<br />Sat Sept 29 &ndash; Blood &amp; Dumplings (San Gabriel Valley true crime tour)<br />Sun Oct 7&ndash; Reyner Banham Loves Los Angeles (architecture/urbanism tour)<br />Sat Oct 20&ndash; The Real Black Dahlia tour<br />Sun Oct 21 &ndash; Where the Action Was (rock history tour)<br />Sat Oct 27 &ndash; Haunts of a Dirty Old Man: Charles Bukowski&#8217;s LA<br />Sun Oct 28 &ndash; Hallowe&#8217;en Horrors featuring Crimebo the Clown</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/09/26/saturday-929-explore-the-san-gabriel-valleys-legacy-of-weird-crimes-sea-monsters-and-great-eats/">Saturday 9/29 &#8211; Explore the San Gabriel Valley&#8217;s legacy of weird crimes, sea monsters and great eats</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://1947project.com/2007/09/26/saturday-929-explore-the-san-gabriel-valleys-legacy-of-weird-crimes-sea-monsters-and-great-eats/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blood &#038; Dumplings Crime Bus Podcast</title>
		<link>https://1947project.com/2007/03/28/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-podcast/</link>
					<comments>https://1947project.com/2007/03/28/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-podcast/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2007 06:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crime Bus Tours]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san gabriel valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Gabriel Valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jacob adelman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lana clarkson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phil spector]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jacob Adelman of the venerable AP rode along with the gang on the Blood &#38; Dumplings Crime Bus Tour on St. Patrick&#8217;s Day, and produced a delightful little audio document of the day for the AP&#8217;s youth-oriented asap section. It includes an overview of the tour, some excerpted crime stories from the tour, and interviews&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://1947project.com/2007/03/28/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-podcast/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Blood &#038; Dumplings Crime Bus Podcast</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/03/28/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-podcast/">Blood &#038; Dumplings Crime Bus Podcast</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>Jacob Adelman of the venerable AP rode along with the gang on the Blood &amp; Dumplings Crime Bus Tour on St. Patrick&#8217;s Day, and produced a delightful little audio document of the day for the AP&#8217;s youth-oriented asap section. It includes an overview of the tour, some excerpted crime stories from the tour, and interviews with a few of the delightful passengers. Why would otherwise normal people choose to spend their Saturday hearing tales of mayhem and horror? <a href="https://asap.ap.org/stories/1330755.s" target="_blank">Click slowly</a> and see&#8230;.</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/03/28/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-podcast/">Blood &#038; Dumplings Crime Bus Podcast</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://1947project.com/2007/03/28/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-podcast/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Blood &#038; Dumplings Crime Bus Tour (March 17, 1pm-6pm)</title>
		<link>https://1947project.com/2007/02/24/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-tour-march-17-1pm-6pm/</link>
					<comments>https://1947project.com/2007/02/24/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-tour-march-17-1pm-6pm/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2007 04:22:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crime Bus Tours]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[El Monte]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monterey park]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san gabriel valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[San Gabriel Valley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Alhambra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[manson family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[phil spector]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If there&#8217;s one thing we at 1947project love even more than uncovering evidence of an incredibly weird forgotten crime, it&#8217;s Chinese food&#8211;especially dumplings! Whether fried or boiled, stuffed with shrimp, pork, pumpkin, fish, scallions or sometimes a little dollop of soup, nothing is more comforting and delicious. With Blood &#38; Dumplings, we&#8217;re combining our favorite&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://1947project.com/2007/02/24/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-tour-march-17-1pm-6pm/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Blood &#038; Dumplings Crime Bus Tour (March 17, 1pm-6pm)</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/02/24/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-tour-march-17-1pm-6pm/">Blood &#038; Dumplings Crime Bus Tour (March 17, 1pm-6pm)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p>If there&#8217;s one thing we at 1947project love even more than uncovering<br />  evidence of an incredibly weird forgotten crime, it&#8217;s Chinese<br />  food&#8211;especially dumplings! Whether fried or boiled, stuffed with<br />  shrimp, pork, pumpkin, fish, scallions or sometimes a little dollop of<br />  soup, nothing is more comforting and delicious.</p>
<p>  With <strong>Blood &amp; Dumplings</strong>, we&#8217;re combining our favorite things to bring<br />  you the first new Crime Bus tour of 2007, a a grim and gleeful descent<br />  into the criminal history of the San Gabriel Valley, including the battling Nazis of El Monte, the chilling (and probably incestuous) Case of the Buried Bride, missing Salvador Dali paintings, the dark history of the Lions Club&#8217;s lion meat BBQs held in eye- and nose-range of hundreds of the lovely beasts, the Man from Mars Bandit (his mystery revealed!), plus Phil Spector, neglected Manson victim Steve Parent, Geneva Ellroy and a peculiar East L.A. link to the JFK assassination, concealed Black Panthers and the coolest trailer parks in the Southland.</p>
<p>Included in the $55 ticket price is a special stop for Chinese comfort food at one of the best dumpling joints in Monterey Park&nbsp; and an afternoon picnic surrounded by real sea monsters.</p>
<p>  Click <a href="https://crimebus.dumplingjoint.com/" target="_blank">here</a> to buy your ticket by paypal, or <a href="https://www.47upgradepath7.richardschave.com//feedback" target="_self">email</a> to reserve a seat that you will purchase with a money order or check.</p>
<p>We hope to see YOU on the Crime Bus!</p>
<p>your hosts,<br />Kim Cooper &amp; Richard Schave </p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/02/24/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-tour-march-17-1pm-6pm/">Blood &#038; Dumplings Crime Bus Tour (March 17, 1pm-6pm)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://1947project.com/2007/02/24/blood-dumplings-crime-bus-tour-march-17-1pm-6pm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
