<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="https://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="https://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>washington &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/washington/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Los Angeles De-Mythified</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 19:47:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-1947logoSquare-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>washington &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>All About the Weird West Adams Tour</title>
		<link>/2006/11/27/all-about-the-weird-west-adams-tour/</link>
					<comments>/2006/11/27/all-about-the-weird-west-adams-tour/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2006 17:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Crime Bus Tours]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crimebo the Clown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[figueroa]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[west adams]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wilshire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jefferson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vermont]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[washington]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[western]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[WHAT: 1947project Weird West Adams Crime Bus Tour, Saturday 12/16/06, 11am-4pm. $47 cost includes snacks, beverages and five-hour luxury coach tour.&#160;LOS ANGELES- Since January, the bloggers at 1947project have taken their Los Angeles crime history research on the road with their lively, mysterious and very popular Crime Bus tours. Past routes have explored the dark &#8230; <a href="/2006/11/27/all-about-the-weird-west-adams-tour/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">All About the Weird West Adams Tour</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>WHAT: 1947project Weird West Adams Crime Bus Tour, Saturday 12/16/06, 11am-4pm. $47 cost includes snacks, beverages and five-hour luxury coach tour.<br />&nbsp;<br />LOS ANGELES- Since January, the bloggers at 1947project have taken their Los Angeles crime history research on the road with their lively, mysterious and very popular Crime Bus tours. Past routes have explored the dark side of Pasadena, the secret history of downtown and the real story of the Black Dahlia case. In December, 1947project offers a new tour celebrating the Beverly Hills of the early 20th century, that grand swath of city just west of downtown: Weird West Adams.</p>
<p>On this five-hour tour, Crime Bus passengers will be treated to detailed descriptions of some of the most notorious, strange and fascinating forgotten tales from the past hundred years, each told at the scene of the crime. They&#8217;ll thrill to the carjacking horror of silent film starlet Myrtle Gonzalez, shiver as Dream Killer Otto Parzyjegla chops his newspaper publisher boss to pieces with the paper-cutting blade, shudder at the pickled poignancy of the murder-by-brandy of Benjamin Weber, marvel at the Krazy Kafitz family and their litany of murder-suicides, attempted husband slayings, Byzantine estate battles and mad bombings, then gag at terrible fate visited on kidnap victim Marion Parker by The Fox. There will be some celebrity sites along the route, including the death scenes of Motown soul sensation Marvin Gaye and 1920s star Angels baseball catcher Gus Sandberg. </p>
<p>And in a special treat for the holiday season, the Crime Bus will toast the Winter Solstice by visiting the city&#8217;s shortest street and remembering 2&#8242; 11&quot; Angelo Rossitto, the charismatic cult actor / newsstand operator (&quot;Freaks,&quot; &quot;Mad Max Beyond Thunderdome&quot;) who famously visited the spot in his teeny-tiny car on 12/21/37.&nbsp; All this, plus a robbery by Pretty Boy Floyd, Prohibition-era houses transformed into secret distilleries, fumigations gone terribly wrong, mashers, bad marriages, rotten drivers, assorted weirdos and a mummified teenage cult priestess.</p>
<p>Upcoming Crime Bus Tours include the 60th Anniversary Real Black Dahlia (January 13, 2007).</p>
<p>Want to reserve a seat for West Adams or the Black Dahlia? Just <a href="https://www.47upgradepath7.richardschave.com//feedback" target="_self">email</a> us with the number of spots you&#8217;d like. <br />&nbsp;</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/11/27/all-about-the-weird-west-adams-tour/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
