<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="https://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="https://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>evelyn winters &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<atom:link href="https://1947project.com/category/evelyn-winters-2/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://1947project.com/</link>
	<description>Los Angeles De-Mythified</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 19:40:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://1947project.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-1947logoSquare-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>evelyn winters &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<link>https://1947project.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Police Grill Pin Boy in Winters Whack</title>
		<link>https://1947project.com/2006/03/13/police-grill-pin-boy-in-winters-whack/</link>
					<comments>https://1947project.com/2006/03/13/police-grill-pin-boy-in-winters-whack/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2006 19:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Assault]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crimes against persons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Downtown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drugs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evelyn winters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kidnapping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[los angeles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[residential hotel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1947]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alcoholism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bowling]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>March 13, 1947 Los Angeles Detectives questioned James Joseph Tiernan Jr., 30, tonight about his movements Monday night, both before and after the time he claimed that Evelyn Winters, 42, left his hotel room at 912 W. Sixth Street. Winters turned up dead just after midnight Tuesday in the railyard at Ducommun Street, her clothes&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://1947project.com/2006/03/13/police-grill-pin-boy-in-winters-whack/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Police Grill Pin Boy in Winters Whack</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2006/03/13/police-grill-pin-boy-in-winters-whack/">Police Grill Pin Boy in Winters Whack</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p>March 13, 1947 Los Angeles Detectives questioned James Joseph Tiernan Jr., 30, tonight about his movements Monday night, both before and after the time he claimed that Evelyn Winters, 42, left his hotel room at 912 W. Sixth Street. Winters turned up dead just after midnight Tuesday in the railyard at <a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;q=Ducommun+St+%26+Center+St,+Los+Angeles,+CA+90012&amp;ll=34.052339,-118.23143&amp;spn=0.01568,0.041757">Ducommun Street</a>, her clothes in disarray, with a blood alcohol level of .28, a nearly fatal proportion. According to Dr. Frederick Newbarr of the Coroner&#8217;s Office, cause of death was blows to the head, exacerbated by the extent of her drunkenness. Tiernan was arrested the next day at the bowling alley at 924 S. Olive Street where he was formerly employed.</p>
<p>Captain Jack Donahoe is following up on Tiernan&#8217;s story. Tiernan admits to knowing Winters&#8211;a former movie industry legal secretary fallen on hard times&#8211;for about two years. He says he met her on Sunday at the public library, then took her to his hotel room. They both liked reading, and alcohol. On Monday night, they were drinking together in the Sixth Street room. Winters left alone between 7:30 and 8 pm. Tiernan stayed in, and that was the last time he saw his<br />
friend Evelyn.</p>
<p>Nathan&#8217;s take on the case is <a href="https://1947project.com/?p=1445" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p>Confidential to 1947project readers: 1947 has been an incredible year, and we hope to see you over at our <a href="../../../../undefined/https://1947project.com/">new digs</a> real soon, where the subject is 1907.</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2006/03/13/police-grill-pin-boy-in-winters-whack/">Police Grill Pin Boy in Winters Whack</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://1947project.com/2006/03/13/police-grill-pin-boy-in-winters-whack/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Winters of Our Discontent</title>
		<link>https://1947project.com/2006/03/13/the-winters-of-our-discontent/</link>
					<comments>https://1947project.com/2006/03/13/the-winters-of-our-discontent/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathan Marsak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2006 19:10:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Assault]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Beating]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crimes against persons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Downtown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drugs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evelyn winters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hotels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kidnapping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[los angeles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nathan marsak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rape]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[residential hotel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[1947]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alcoholism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bowling]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Note: Kim&#8217;s take on this case is here. 1947:  a lot of women-killing, a lot of booze. It&#8217;s enough to turn one into a teetotaling sub. Almost. And here, a woman killing herself. With booze. Nowadays, her family would call up A&#38;E and sheï¿½d be on Intervention. Perfect fodder for the show&#8211;someone: somewhere once, nowhere&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://1947project.com/2006/03/13/the-winters-of-our-discontent/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">The Winters of Our Discontent</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2006/03/13/the-winters-of-our-discontent/">The Winters of Our Discontent</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p>Note: Kim&#8217;s take on this case is <a href="https://1947project.com/?p=1443" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
<p>1947:  a lot of women-killing, a lot of booze. It&#8217;s enough to turn one into a teetotaling sub. Almost. And here, a woman killing herself. With booze. Nowadays, her family would call up A&amp;E and sheï¿½d be on Intervention. Perfect fodder for the show&#8211;someone: somewhere once, nowhere now. Our identified family member has hit bottom. Get them into treatment. God, give me the strength to blame those who did this to me, to accuse those who didn&#8217;t, and the wisdom to know the difference&#8230;a lifetime of coffee, cigarettes and forced clapping after each and every utterance. Evelyn Winters was described as &#8220;brilliant&#8221; by those who knew her, a legal eagle for the studio system since she was 23, til her alcholism caught up with her and she was shitcanned from the film colony at 37. Was there sensitivity training in the workplace for those who still suffer? This is 1947. The only place you&#8217;ll be happy, joyous and free is in the afterlife. For more information about alcohol, ask a parent or teacher! Or go <a href="https://1947project.blogspot.com/2005/05/diana-goddess-of-highball.html">here</a>. The elephant in the copy room went to the elephant graveyard: skid row. Where does a homeless 800-lb. gorilla sleep? Anywhere it can. And so forth. Evelyn&#8217;s last known address&#8211;September, 1946&#8211;was here, at 2822 Rowena: <img src="//static.flickr.com/50/112348083_fb2f2cd034_o.jpg" alt="" border="0" /></p>
<p>But in the months prior to her assault and murder she had been living in the beer parlors on Hill and Figueroa, keeping what was left of her belongings in a liquor store. <img src="//static.flickr.com/54/111145990_02afade9c8_o.gif" alt="" border="0" /> She was out carousing, divorced, jobless, though with, I&#8217;d wager, a mind still keen and ticking, before she was found nearly nude, beaten, and dragged for some way, near the Ducommun Street railroad right-of-way, here: <img src="//static.flickr.com/54/112350056_fd75398267_o.jpg" alt="" border="0" /> Evelyn, homeless, now has a homeless encampment on her site. So, then there&#8217;s this Tiernan character. <img src="//static.flickr.com/56/111145553_0ee5a3d687_o.gif" alt="" border="0" /> He&#8217;s twelve years Evelyn&#8217;s junior. A former employee of the Angelus Bowling and Billiard Recreation Center, <img src="//static.flickr.com/19/111062128_6ea3aec4cd_o.jpg" alt="" border="0" /> which is now a parking lot: <img src="//static.flickr.com/40/112357566_2e01b1afb9_o.jpg" alt="" border="0" /> (for more on prewar bowling alleys, go <a href="https://1947project.blogspot.com/2005/06/sunset-center-et-al.html">here</a>) &#8212; he takes Evelyn to the Albany Hotel at 912 W. Sixth. He drinks with her there for a day and change and, if he is to be believed, she departs between 7:30 and 8pm. She is found at 12:10am. The Albany, where she may have had her last drink, or did not, is gone: <img src="//static.flickr.com/56/112342750_6fd9c0bf5d_o.jpg" alt="" border="0" /> (Sanwa Bank Plaza, AC Martin, 1990) Never did find a vintage image of the Albany; some flavor of the wiped-out neighborhood&#8211;one block west: <img src="//static.flickr.com/39/111137989_fc7d808fde_o.jpg" alt="" border="0" /> And one block east: <img src="//static.flickr.com/52/111137927_4da48a1552_o.jpg" alt="" border="0" /> But why the hotel room? We don&#8217;t know. Tiernan didn&#8217;t live at the Albany. He lived at the Armondale, at 728 South Flower. <img src="//static.flickr.com/39/111137834_8728ca620a_o.jpg" alt="" border="0" /> Its site today: <img src="//static.flickr.com/48/112340422_60faea0966_o.jpg" alt="" border="0" /> First off, what, already, is up with the Armondale Hotel? It has that &#8220;built on Indian burial ground&#8221; cachet that money can&#8217;t buy. Perhaps it was simply built over one of those giant magnets. The kind that attract ne&#8217;er-do-wells. The place had trouble attached from the get-go. Dale Carleton, developer and proprietor of the spanking-new 1914 Armondale, is sued by wifey Marie for a sizable share of his $250,000 net worth. Mrs. Carleton names a Ms. Helen Williams&#8211;Armondale telephone girl whose duties apparently went above and beyond the working of switchboard&#8211;as correspondent. 1919. Wilbert Garrison, 28, son of a wealthy publisher in New York, drove across country with a buddy and they holed up in the Armondale. A week later Wilbert left in his room his money, valuables, and a note indicating that he did not want to be a burden on others, and as such was ending his life. Despite the best efforts of the Nick Harris detective agency (who calls the cops in 1919), Wilbert is never found. 1930. Mrs. Louis Valenzuella, 40, ex-wife of Deputy Sheriff Valenzuella, is found dead in the Armondale of a suspected drug overdose. 1939. Washed-up boxer Louis Menney, 22, Armondale resident, is tackled by a priest after he sexually assaulted a 62 year-old woman in a church at 9th (now James M. Woods) and Green. Turns out he&#8217;d&#8211;moletsed? raped?&#8211;the papers will only mention &#8220;morals offenses&#8221;&#8211;a nine year-old in the church as well. Moreover, he&#8217;d done his business with a six year-old girl on the corner of 11th (now Chick Hearn) and Georgia, and also kidnapped and robbed an Agnes M&#8212;&#8211; and sexually assaulted a Margaret L&#8212;&#8211; in a church on West Adams; since the kidnapping charge is death penalty territory, we can only hope the Armondale&#8217;s most famous resident ended up in the proper hands. <img src="//static.flickr.com/47/111137863_f0f8b99b55_o.jpg" alt="" border="0" /> 1948. Francis Sylvester, of the Armondale, works across the street at the Western Union at 741 South Flower. Sylvester wires untold sums in care of himself to small outlying towns, where there are no Western Union offices, and destroys the records of the transactions. And 1965. Percy Hatch, 65, who had been in the hotel since 1957, started talking crazy-talk. As in, a loggorhea of obscenities for two straight weeks. Behind the Armondale registration desk was manager Nancy Furlow, 62, who, finally fed up with her repeated warnings, reached for the phone, and was shot dead by Hatch with one bullet. Hatch therewith turned the gun on himself. Shortly thereafter the Armondale was felled and a rather ill-advised Broadway was built on the site. Now a Macy&#8217;s, it resembles a Dawn mall on a slow day. For more on this exercise in brown, please go <a href="https://1947project.blogspot.com/2005/09/723-west-eighth-to-day.html">here</a>. Tiernan had been reading with Evelyn at Central Library for a couple years. They would read, or shack up and drink, and maybe he&#8217;d talk bowling and maybe she&#8217;d talk law, but probably not. Neither he nor anyone else was ever charged. And so goes the final post of 1947. Soon there will be <a href="https://1947project.blogspot.com/2005/05/locust-avenue-to-day.html">another</a> liquor-infused ladykilling, and <a href="https://1947project.blogspot.com/2005/07/elmyra-north-main.html">another</a>, and Evelyn will be forgotten by all but her mother and best barfly pals and her killer, and God willing, she will become part of us.</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2006/03/13/the-winters-of-our-discontent/">The Winters of Our Discontent</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://1947project.com/2006/03/13/the-winters-of-our-discontent/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
