<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="https://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="https://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>WCTU &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/wctu/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description>Los Angeles De-Mythified</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 20:39:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-1947logoSquare-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>WCTU &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Of Boxing and Booze</title>
		<link>/2006/08/14/of-boxing-and-booze/</link>
					<comments>/2006/08/14/of-boxing-and-booze/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathan Marsak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2006 08:32:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[alcohol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boxing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nathan marsak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Suicide]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Georgia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pugilism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[WCTU]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[August 14, 1907Los Angeles Colonel and Cracker alike are swarming our borders! Dateline&#8212;The Peach State&#8212;Sherman&#8217;s march to the coast was less an indignity than that done by the last state election:&#160; all liquor establishments are to be outlawed on January 1.&#160; Now the march is of capital out of Georgia&#8212;an estimated $3,000,000 in taxes and &#8230; <a href="/2006/08/14/of-boxing-and-booze/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Of Boxing and Booze</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>August 14, 1907<img loading="lazy" width="333" height="266" border="0" align="right" src="//static.flickr.com/84/214870602_bc4a002f4e_o.gif" alt="julepnomore" title="julepnomore" /><br />Los Angeles</p>
<p>Colonel and Cracker alike are swarming our borders!</p>
<p>Dateline&mdash;The Peach State&mdash;Sherman&rsquo;s march to the coast was less an indignity than that done by the last state election:&nbsp; all liquor establishments are to be outlawed on January 1.&nbsp; Now the march is of capital out of Georgia&mdash;an estimated $3,000,000 in taxes and licenses in 08.&nbsp; As the steady, self-righteous hand of the WCTU has not as yet clamped itself upon the great metropolis of Los Angeles, wholesalers and barmen alike are arriving en masse. &nbsp;</p>
<p>Those in the LA liquor trade welcome our Reb brethren, at least so that they may assure their bit by securing locations and concessions for the newcomers.&nbsp; The local liquor lobby has hit up City Hall for an extension of the Liquor Zone, and has petitioned to increase the number of saloons in LA to 250.</p>
<p>Despite a collective Angeleno fondness for drink, it is the civic duty of 1947project to provide a temperance lesson:</p>
<p>Some years ago, Harry Stuart was a pugilist of renown, his nose broken repeatedly in the ply of his noble trade.&nbsp; Then, as a barkeep on West Third, he was LA&rsquo;s authority on the pugilistic arts, and oft served as referee for Tom McCarey&rsquo;s Fight Club, which held forth in the old Hazard&rsquo;s Pavilion (in 1907 the site of the great Auditorium facing Central Park).&nbsp; Stuart was famous for the way he yelled &ldquo;b-r-e-a-k!&rdquo; that amused spectators; his downfall was an unpopular decision in the ring which awarded a trophy to colored boxer Billy Woods, over Al Neil.</p>
<p>Bad luck turned worse after Stuart built a fight club at the westerly end of the Third Street tunnel, which prompted uproar from the tony neighbors.&nbsp; The City Council passed an ordinance confining such clubs to a certain district in the Eighth Ward.&nbsp; To make matters all the more discouraging, Stuart was stung by a spider on his left eye, destroying the sight thereof. &nbsp;</p>
<p>He found menial employment soliciting monies for a weekly publication, and after collecting nearly $100 ($2,052 USD 2006), decided to go on the drinking spree to end all drinking sprees.&nbsp; It lasted three weeks.</p>
<p>After the money was gone and the booze was consumed, he wrote notes to his wife in San Francisco, the Los Angeles Coroner, and his employer.&nbsp; In them he stated that drink had put him &ldquo;down and out&rdquo; and that he had nothing to live for.&nbsp; From his note to the Coroner:&nbsp; &ldquo;Booze has been the cause of my downfall, and I am daffy&hellip;my wife will meet the expense of having my worthless body burned.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Stuart, after losing his last fight, this one to a bottle, swallowed a solution of bromide in his Bunker Hill room at 244 North Grand.<br /><img loading="lazy" width="444" height="301" border="0" align="absbottom" src="//static.flickr.com/85/214870566_59f19cd327_o.gif" alt="stuart" title="stuart" /></p>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2006/08/14/of-boxing-and-booze/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
