<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>martin albornoz &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<atom:link href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/tag/martin-albornoz/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/</link>
	<description>Los Angeles De-Mythified</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 19:47:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-1947logoSquare-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>martin albornoz &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>L.A. Alternative Publisher Martin Albornoz stiffs 1947project</title>
		<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2006/12/20/l-a-alternative-publisher-martin-albornoz-stiffs-1947project/</link>
					<comments>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2006/12/20/l-a-alternative-publisher-martin-albornoz-stiffs-1947project/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2006 19:22:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[North East LA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[los angeles alternative]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[martin albornoz]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>(See update below)&#160; Gentle reader, How pleased I was, during Sunset Junction week in late August, when the L.A. Alternative published an issue of their free weekly featuring my three-page pull-out crime map detailing the historic oddities and horrors of the Sunset Junction neighborhood. I heard from folks who attended the street fair that it&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2006/12/20/l-a-alternative-publisher-martin-albornoz-stiffs-1947project/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">L.A. Alternative Publisher Martin Albornoz stiffs 1947project</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2006/12/20/l-a-alternative-publisher-martin-albornoz-stiffs-1947project/">L.A. Alternative Publisher Martin Albornoz stiffs 1947project</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p><strong>(See update below)</strong>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Gentle reader,</p>
<p>How pleased I was, during Sunset Junction week in late August, when the L.A. Alternative published an issue of their free weekly featuring my three-page pull-out crime map detailing the historic oddities and horrors of the Sunset Junction neighborhood. I heard from folks who attended the street fair that it was a big hit, with people walking around checking addresses and shuddering. (The Sunset Junction story can now only be seen <a href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/?p=1656" target="_self">right here</a> at 1947project.) </p>
<p>A month after my story came out, publisher Martin Albornoz <a href="http://www.laobserved.com/archive/2006/09/la_alternative_rip_update.php" target="_blank">announced</a> the paper was folding, but that he hoped to continue publishing online. Although at this point I was wondering where my payment was, I still dashed off a friendly email telling Martin that my husband Richard and I would be happy to meet with him and give him some ideas about how to  pull this off, as we believed he and his writers had a lot to offer the community. He never replied.</p>
<p>Nor did Martin reply to my repeated emails, as the weeks ticked away with no sign of the $250 payment for the feature. I sent a certified letter demanding the money, which went uncollected. So I finally phoned and left a message, which resulted in the following email on November 27:</p>
<div>
<div><em>Hello Kim, </em></div>
<div><em>&nbsp;</em></div>
<div><em>I just heard your message and Lesley had forwarded me your email last week. I&#8217;m not sure how much you know about the office and the state of LA Alternative but we aren&#8217;t in business anymore. We stopped publishing the print and online version about a month ago. I haven&#8217;t been in the office for about a month, I started a full time job, so I haven&#8217;t had a chance to pick up any mail or cut any checks. We are trying to cover as many outstanding obligations as possible&nbsp;when money trickles in from our advertisers. </em></div>
<div><em>&nbsp;</em></div>
<div><em>You are on the list of people who need to be paid. I will be writing some checks in the next few weeks. Thanks for all your help and thanks for your understanding.</em></div>
<div><em>&nbsp;</em></div>
<div><em>Best,</em></div>
<p><span class="sg"> </p>
<div><em><span class="st">Martin</span></em></div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div>To which I replied:</div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div>
<div><em>Hi <span class="st">Martin</span>,</p>
<p>Yes, I am aware that you stopped publishing. In fact, you may recall<br />that I emailed you offering to advise you about your online options,<br />but received no reply.</p>
<p>Nonetheless, I wrote a story several months prior to the LAA closing,<br />and am owed $250 for it. I would appreciate your putting me high on<br />the list of people to be paid. I will extend the courtesy of<br />additional three weeks to you before pursuing other options. Please<br />ensure I receive payment by December 18.</p>
<p>I heard from Michele that Lesley thinks she remembers sending me a<br />check. So it is possible that you have already tried to pay me and the<br />check was lost in the mail. I would appreciate your checking on this,<br />and recutting the check if that is the case.</p>
<p>I would also appreciate it if you would mail me a stack of copies of<br />the issue with my cover story. Bulk rate is fine.</p>
<p>Thanks, and best regards,<br /></em></div>
</div>
<div><em><span class="sg">Kim Cooper</span></em></div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div>He did not reply. Two days ago, I emailed to remind Martin it has been three weeks, and I have still not been paid. </div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div>
<div><em>Hi <span class="st">Martin</span>,</p>
<p>It has been three weeks since I last heard that &quot;in a few weeks&quot; you<br />would be writing checks, and there has been no sign of payment for my<br />cover story, nor of the copies of that issue that I asked for.</p>
<p>Are you prepared to make good on this debt now, or must I go forward<br />with the plan for publicizing the non-payment and filing in small<br />claims court that I spelled out previously [in the certified letter that I later emailed to Martin]?</p>
<p>Please spare us both any additional bother and awkwardness and send me<br />$250 now, or let me know exactly when you will be doing so. I am<br />willing to work with you, but not to wait indefinitely for payment,<br />especially if you don&#8217;t keep me informed of the situation.</p>
<p>thanks,<br /></em></div>
</div>
<div><em><span class="q">Kim Cooper</span></em></div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div>He ignored that email, too. And so it is with no pleasure that I am going public with this dishonorable tale, in hopes that it will inspire Martin to take responsibility for his debt and to let any other writers in the same situation know that they are not alone.</div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div>I&#8217;ve known Martin socially for more than a decade. I&#8217;ve consigned zines in his former zine shop in Silver Lake and had a Scram release party there. I&#8217;ve had nice conversations with him, publisher-to-publisher. I&#8217;m really shocked by how this has played out, and apologize to all of you for airing his dirty drawers here on 1947project. But I do think it&#8217;s important to shine a light on wrong-doing, and so here&#8217;s a blast of pure white.</div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div>Martin, send me my money, and pay off your other contributors. It&#8217;s the honorable thing to do, and it will make the next stage of your life more tolerable. Otherwise, I guess I&#8217;ll see you in small claims court. <em>What A Drag.</em></div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div>*</div>
<div>Email received from Martin, 2pm December 20:</div>
<div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div><em>Hello Kim, </em></div>
<div><em>&nbsp;</em></div>
<div><em>I just got word from someone that you&#8217;ve sent out an email about L.A. Alternative owing you money. I really am sorry about us owing you money, but we can&#8217;t pay with what we don&#8217;t have. We are owed money by some large advertisers and we owe lots of vendors money, hence,&nbsp;we went out of business.&nbsp;So, other than looking kind of petty, I&#8217;m not sure what you&#8217;ve accomplished. Like&nbsp;I mentioned to you, the newspaper will be filing for bankruptcy,&nbsp;which means you&#8217;ll get a letter stating that you&#8217;re owed money and once the process goes through, you&#8217;ll get&nbsp;your $250 out of the&nbsp;sale of the assets. With what&#8217;s owed to some vendors, I don&#8217;t believe there will be much left&nbsp;over but I do hope that you won&#8217;t be affected too harshly by this outcome. It really&nbsp;is unfortunate when a business can&#8217;t survive, but considering the&nbsp;hostile business environment that newspapers&nbsp;are currently in, this may become more common. Our self-published paper did give the huge corporate weeklies a run for the their money and thank you for being a part of that. </em></div>
<div><em>&nbsp;</em></div>
<div><em>Good luck with your project, which btw, we supported in free&nbsp;ads announcing your readings and in the article which prominently mentioned your website.</em></div>
<p><span class="sg"> </p>
<div><em>&nbsp;</em></div>
<div><em>&#8211;Martin</em></div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div>My reply:</div>
<div>
<div>&nbsp;</div>
<div><em>Dear Martin,</p>
<p>Why is it that the only way I can get you to communicate with me is to<br />send out a mass email and post on my blog? You have had several weeks<br />in which to respond to my polite request for information on when I<br />would be paid, and you&#8217;ve ignored me. You never mentioned bankruptcy.<br />You actually said you would be sending checks out within several<br />weeks, which did not happen, so I emailed you again, waited two days,<br />and then went public.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m very appreciative of the support of the local press for the<br />1947project, and am always willing to give time and assistance to<br />reporters who have questions. But I worked for two weeks writing and<br />researching a huge story for your paper, which is something very<br />different.</p>
<p>I wish you only the best, and hope that you will see fit to honor your<br />promise to pay for this story. And it would be quite a nice gesture of<br />goodwill if you were to send me those extra copies of my feature that<br />I have asked you for several times.</p>
<p>I will update the blog entry with any good news you can send, which<br />should be an added incentive to you to do the right thing.</p>
<p>best regards,<br /></em></div>
<p><em><span class="q">Kim Cooper</span></em> </div>
<p></span>&nbsp;</div>
<p>  </span></div>
<p></div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2006/12/20/l-a-alternative-publisher-martin-albornoz-stiffs-1947project/">L.A. Alternative Publisher Martin Albornoz stiffs 1947project</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2006/12/20/l-a-alternative-publisher-martin-albornoz-stiffs-1947project/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
