<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>electricity &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<atom:link href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/category/electricity-3/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/</link>
	<description>Los Angeles De-Mythified</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 20:38:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-1947logoSquare-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>electricity &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>The Battle of East 71st Street</title>
		<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/01/04/the-battle-of-east-71st-street/</link>
					<comments>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/01/04/the-battle-of-east-71st-street/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2008 01:26:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[protest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[South Central]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The wacko file]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[women]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[power]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>January 3, 1927South Los Angeles The men came marching onto County land, with their boots and their buckets and their shovels and their poles, and the ladies of East 71st Street, just east of Hooper Avenue, came out of their little bungalows, leaving their babies and their breakfast dishes and their washboards and their bougainvilleas,&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/01/04/the-battle-of-east-71st-street/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">The Battle of East 71st Street</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/01/04/the-battle-of-east-71st-street/">The Battle of East 71st Street</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div><a title="The Battle of East 71st Street by richardschave, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/richardschave/2164657894/"><img loading="lazy" width="500" height="285" border="0" alt="The Battle of East 71st Street" src="//farm3.static.flickr.com/2399/2164657894_441b417785.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>January 3, 1927<br />South Los Angeles</p>
<p>The men came marching onto County land, with their boots and their buckets and their shovels and their poles, and the ladies of <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&#038;hl=en&#038;geocode=&#038;time=&#038;date=&#038;ttype=&#038;q=east+71st+street+and+hooper,+los+angeles,+ca&#038;sll=37.0625,-95.677068&#038;sspn=56.375557,98.085938&#038;ie=UTF8&#038;ll=33.976152,-118.251134&#038;spn=0.003648,0.005987&#038;t=h&#038;z=17&#038;om=1&#038;layer=c&#038;cbll=33.976855,-118.252072" target="_blank">East 71st Street</a>, just east of Hooper Avenue, came out of their little bungalows, leaving their babies and their breakfast dishes and their washboards and their bougainvilleas, and they met there, in the middle of the road, and looked each other up and down. </p>
<p>&quot;Why have you come to our little street?&quot; asked the ladies.<br />&quot;To install high tension electrical wires,&quot; the men replied.<br />&quot;Down the middle of our street?&quot;<br />&quot;Down the middle of your street.&quot;<br />&quot;Like hell you will!&quot; was the ladies&#8217; retort. And when the workmen returned to sink their poles on Monday morning, they found an angry mob of females who congregated around the various spots where holes were to be sunk and planted their bodies in the way of any work. One octogenarian brought a chair out and sat atop the digging spot, while others stood their ground and glared. At lunch time, other women came out and changed places, so no child would go without its meal.</p>
<p>The men retreated, not willing to spill female blood or risk their own safety further. On further investigation, it was revealed the city has not obtained the proper county permit to plant any such power line down 71st Street, so any such erection would be delayed indefinitely. And the next day, a spokesman for the work crew said, &quot;They not only won, they routed us altogether. There&#8217;ll be six feet of ice at Sixth and Broadway before some of our men venture on Seventy-first street again. We ceased operations because we are not putting up any poles or lines on any street where the people object to them. Nothing will be done unless we can come to some agreement with the women.&quot;</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s to the heroines of the Battle of East 71st Street: Mrs. P. R. Bottomly of 1348 East 71st Street, Mrs. H. B. Dawson of #1332, Mrs. M. M. Schnell of #1342 and Mrs. W.J. Kline of #1315 and those who sat for the photograph (L-R): Mrs. Louisa H. Orr (aged 82), Mrs. W. A. Grubbs, Mrs. G. S. McIntyre (provisional general), Mrs. M. Robertson (aide-de-camp), Mrs. R. Jackson (chief of staff) and Mrs. Louise Dixson. For sisterhood is powerful, NIMBYism is nothing new in Los Angeles, and who the hell wants power lines cluttering up their view?</p>
<p><a title="The Battle of East 71st Street by richardschave, on Flickr" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/richardschave/2164657896/"><img loading="lazy" width="329" height="79" border="0" alt="The Battle of East 71st Street" src="//farm3.static.flickr.com/2048/2164657896_411e41fd73_o.png" /></a></p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/01/04/the-battle-of-east-71st-street/">The Battle of East 71st Street</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2008/01/04/the-battle-of-east-71st-street/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A chunk of bog and thou</title>
		<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/09/07/a-chunk-of-bog-and-thou/</link>
					<comments>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/09/07/a-chunk-of-bog-and-thou/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2007 22:38:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Burning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The wacko file]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[West LA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wilshire]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>September 7, 1927Los Angeles When, oh when, oh when will something be done to soothe the smoldering peat fires that spill noxious smoke and gas from the vicinity of Jefferson and Hauser Streets in the Baldwin Hills? For more than two years the fire has crept inexorably deeper into the peat beds, and now twelve&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/09/07/a-chunk-of-bog-and-thou/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">A chunk of bog and thou</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/09/07/a-chunk-of-bog-and-thou/">A chunk of bog and thou</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>September 7, 1927<br />Los Angeles</p>
<p>When, oh when, oh when will something be done to soothe the smoldering peat fires that spill noxious smoke and gas from the vicinity of J<a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&#038;hl=en&#038;geocode=&#038;q=Jefferson+and+Hauser,+los+angeles,+ca&#038;sll=34.04458,-118.24896&#038;sspn=0.008161,0.013733&#038;ie=UTF8&#038;ll=34.026646,-118.365154&#038;spn=0.008163,0.013733&#038;t=k&#038;z=16&#038;iwloc=addr&#038;om=1" target="_blank">efferson and Hauser Streets</a> in the Baldwin Hills? For more than two years the fire has crept inexorably deeper into the peat beds, and now twelve acres are burning just under the topsoil, endangering the health of 200,000 local lungs and the ankles of any local foolish enough to tramp through the booby-trapped fields. Forget the living! What of the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bog_body" target="_blank">mummies</a>?!</p>
<p>Former City Councilman Mallard has issues a plea on behalf of his neighborhood that the City Council take this &quot;rank poison&quot; threat seriously and extinguish the blaze immediately. He even tells them how to do it: through steam shovels that can expose the burning beds, so water can be introduced. Of course, Mallard&#8217;s suggestion that the fire be fought in the manner of William Mulholland&#8217;s aqueduct project&mdash;get it done first, then get the permits&mdash;seems in retrospect to be in somewhat less than good taste, but the St. Francis dam disaster is still six months away, and the Mullholland name an untarnished example of Angeleno ingenuity.</p>
<p>*</p>
<p>In New York City, pioneer developer Gaylord Wilshire has died. In recent years, he <a href="http://www.thebakken.org/artifacts/wilshire.htm" target="_blank">devoted</a> himself to promoting an electric &quot;health belt&quot; of his own invention, the &ldquo;I-ON-A-CO.&rdquo;</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/09/07/a-chunk-of-bog-and-thou/">A chunk of bog and thou</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/09/07/a-chunk-of-bog-and-thou/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Signs of the Times</title>
		<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2006/11/06/signs-of-the-times/</link>
					<comments>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2006/11/06/signs-of-the-times/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathan Marsak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2006 04:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[booze]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boxing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Downtown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nathan marsak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[signage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mayor Harper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[signs]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>November 5, 1907Los Angeles Just as an innocent toke of reefer leads to a lifetime of laudanum addiction, everybody knows that electric signs lead to&#8230;neon! Neon wouldn&#8217;t be introduced to the United States until 1923 (specifically, at the Earl C. Anthony Packard dealership, 10th &#38; Hope Street).&#160; That first reefer toke, though&#8230;that was the electric&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2006/11/06/signs-of-the-times/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Signs of the Times</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2006/11/06/signs-of-the-times/">Signs of the Times</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p>November 5, 1907<img loading="lazy" width="300" height="311" border="0" align="right" src="//static.flickr.com/110/290191355_8a62baf5d1_o.gif" alt="boozesign" title="boozesign" /><br />Los Angeles </p>
<p>Just as an innocent toke of reefer leads to a lifetime of laudanum addiction, everybody knows that electric signs lead to&hellip;neon!</p>
<p>Neon wouldn&rsquo;t be introduced to the United States until 1923 (specifically, at the Earl C. Anthony Packard dealership, 10th &amp; Hope Street).&nbsp; That first reefer toke, though&hellip;that was the electric sign&hellip;</p>
<p>Property owners of 1907 argue that electric signs, particularly those of the swinging variety which jut from the fa&ccedil;ades of buildings, make the streets look tawdry.&nbsp; Moreover, they nullify the illumination systems on principal business streets, and will become eyesores and nuisances.</p>
<p>The Mayor, however, is outspoken in favor of electric signs.&nbsp; They illuminate business thoroughfares, and are an ornament to the city.&nbsp; A man of vision, our Mayor Harper.</p>
<p>But what to do, then, with the Jim &ldquo;de champ&rdquo; Jeffries&rsquo; new saloon sign on South Spring?&nbsp; He has had one built and installed, swung over the sidewalk, &ldquo;bearing in letters as big as one of his mitts the magic pugilistic name.&rdquo;</p>
<p>While this type of signage violates numerous and sundry City ordinances, the Board of Public Works has ignored similar signs in the downtown area that advertise caf&eacute;s and theaters, who are crying foul in that municipal authorities have allowed such signs to hang for the last year.&nbsp; Because of Jeffries&rsquo; transgression, he and all other sign owners received letters from the City Attorney demanding the removal of any and all projecting signage, the worry being that should these signs become commonplace, &ldquo;the sidewalks would be converted into tunnels darkened and obstructed by a covering of advertising signs.&rdquo; </p>
<p>Moreover, a proposed ordinance shall prohibit signage advertising liquor.&nbsp; Can this be?</p>
<p>Mayor Harper stands firm.&nbsp; What will become of our city?</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" width="256" height="405" border="0" align="bottom" src="//static.flickr.com/122/290179644_6b47e5b767_o.jpg" alt="electricyouth" title="electricyouth" />Here&rsquo;s a vision of the future:&nbsp; electric signage along Broadway, ca. 1920, as pictured in, uh, <a href="http://losangelesneonbook.com/" target="_blank">this book</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2006/11/06/signs-of-the-times/">Signs of the Times</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2006/11/06/signs-of-the-times/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
