<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="https://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="https://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>entrepreneurs &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<atom:link href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/tag/entrepreneurs-3/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/</link>
	<description>Los Angeles De-Mythified</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 21:39:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-1947logoSquare-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>entrepreneurs &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Is Nothing Sacred?</title>
		<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/07/10/is-nothing-sacred/</link>
					<comments>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/07/10/is-nothing-sacred/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lynn Peril]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2007 18:05:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Downtown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lynn Peril]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Victimless crimes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bootleggers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ice cream]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>July 10, 1927Los Angeles First peanuts and now the All-American ice cream cone. Is there no treat safe from the bootlegger&#8217;s evil maw? Assistant Federal prohibition administrator Frank E. Benedict today announced the discovery of what was called &#34;one of the most completely equipped distilleries&#34; ever found in Los Angeles, hidden in the innocent guise&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/07/10/is-nothing-sacred/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Is Nothing Sacred?</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/07/10/is-nothing-sacred/">Is Nothing Sacred?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p>July 10, 1927<br />Los Angeles</p>
<p>  <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/lperil/767858461/" title="Photo Sharing"><img loading="lazy" width="252" height="368" border="0" src="//farm2.static.flickr.com/1416/767858461_c2d9733283_o.jpg" alt="Is nothing sacred?" /></a>  </p>
<p>First <a href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/?p=1989">peanuts</a> and now the All-American ice cream cone. Is there no treat safe from the bootlegger&#8217;s evil maw? Assistant Federal prohibition administrator Frank E. Benedict today announced the discovery of  what was called &quot;one of the most completely equipped distilleries&quot; ever found in Los Angeles, hidden in the innocent guise of an ice cream cone factory.   </p>
<p>A curious fact brought the plant (located at <a title="Location of distillery." target="_blank" href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&#038;hl=en&#038;geocode=&#038;q=354-1%2F2+West+Manchester+Avenue,+los+angeles,+ca&#038;sll=37.0625,-95.677068&#038;sspn=25.761936,57.744141&#038;ie=UTF8&#038;ll=33.961586,-118.279066&#038;spn=0.006567,0.014098&#038;z=16&#038;om=1">354-1/2 West Manchester Avenue</a>) to the attention of eagle-eyed prohibition agents: business appeared to be flourishing, yet no deliveries were seen leaving the building. Further investigation ensued. When proprietor James Kanich was informed that the interior measurements of the shop matched those he previously provided to agents, his response was &quot;a flippant remark&quot; that led Benedict to measure the building&#8217;s exterior as well. A twenty-three foot discrepancy was thus discovered. Benedict returned inside, sounded the wall with a hammer, found a weak spot, and chopped into the wallboard. Behind it stood a 500-gallon still in full operation. Four thousand gallons of mash were ready for use at the top of a nearby stairway, and forty five-gallon cans of grain alcohol were packed in heavy paper cartons ostensibly used for freshly baked ice cream cones. The distilling room was accessible only through a narrow closet door which, when closed, appeared to be a solid wall. Meanwhile, a thorough check of the main building yielded stale ice cream cones and cone-making machinery filled with cobwebs.   </p>
<p>Both Kanich and his wife, Mary, denied knowledge of the still. Mrs. Kanich told agents that she and her husband were the innocent victims of a group who financed the cone factory, led by a man she could identify only as &quot;Harry.&quot;   </p>
<p>The Kaniches were arrested for violation of the Volstead Act. Benedict promised further arrests would be made.  </p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/07/10/is-nothing-sacred/">Is Nothing Sacred?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/07/10/is-nothing-sacred/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Other Hilton Sisters</title>
		<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/07/03/the-other-hilton-sisters/</link>
					<comments>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/07/03/the-other-hilton-sisters/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lynn Peril]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 Jul 2007 00:51:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hollywood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lynn Peril]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vaudeville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[conjoined twins]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[freaks]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>July 3, 1927Los Angeles Violet and Daisy Hilton are not hotel heiresses. They must work for a living, which is why you will find them at the Pantages theater this week. Nor do they resort to flashing their lady parts for attention. In fact, it may be physically difficult for them to do so: this&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/07/03/the-other-hilton-sisters/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">The Other Hilton Sisters</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/07/03/the-other-hilton-sisters/">The Other Hilton Sisters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p>July 3, 1927<br />Los Angeles  </p>
<p><a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/lperil/698370240/" title="Photo Sharing"><img loading="lazy" width="213" height="432" border="0" src="//farm2.static.flickr.com/1367/698370240_b214b99b24_o.jpg" alt="The other Hilton sisters" /></a>  <a href="https://phreeque.tripod.com/hilton_sisters.html" /></p>
<p><a href="https://phreeque.tripod.com/hilton_sisters.html">Violet and Daisy Hilton</a> are not hotel heiresses. They must work for a living, which is why you will find them at the Pantages theater this week. Nor do they resort to flashing their lady parts for attention. In fact, it may be physically difficult for them to do so:  this set of Hilton sisters has been joined at the hips and buttocks since their birth nineteen years ago.  </p>
<p>Armed with the latest novels and a Pekinese dog named Boy, Violet and Daisy arrived in Los Angeles tonight from San Antonio, Texas. The twins were accompanied by their aunt, Mrs. Myer Myers, who noted that their conjoined condition does not hinder their performance of the <a href=" https://www.streetswing.com/histmain/z3blkbtm.htm">Black Bottom</a>. When not thus engaged onstage, she told reporters, the girls study with a private tutor.  </p>
<p>The twins profess to be a happy pair. &quot;We never quarrel,&quot; Violet told reporters waiting at the train station. &quot;What&rsquo;s the use?&quot;  </p>
<p align="center">* * * * *  </p>
<p>What was the use, indeed? Especially when reality was so much harsher than the Hilton twins let on to reporters in 1927. Myers, for example, was not their aunt. Two weeks after their birth in Brighton, England, in 1908, Violet and Daisy were &quot;adopted&quot; by their unwed mother&#8217;s landlady, Mary Hilton, who immediately put them on display. When Hilton died, the twins were &quot;willed&quot; to Edith Myers, the wife of a carnival balloon salesman. Myers and her husband physically abused Violet and Daisy at the same time they exploited them on stage&mdash;and kept their earnings.  </p>
<p>In 1915, Violet, Daisy, and the Myerses moved to the United States. By the 1920s, the pretty pair of conjoined twins were a sensation on the vaudeville circuit, where they danced, sang, and played the clarinet and saxophone. They were also implicated in their advance man&#8217;s divorce action. Dean Jensen&#8217;s recent biography suggests that both Violet and Daisy had in fact slept with William Oliver at the time his wife sued to dissolve their marriage.  </p>
<p>By 1931, Violet and Daisy had had enough of the Myerses. They found an attorney who helped them break their contract, and took their career into their own hands. They appeared in Tod Browning&#8217;s classic movie, <em>Freaks</em>, in 1932.  </p>
<p>The following year,  twenty-one states refused to issue a wedding license to Violet and her fianc&eacute;. That relationship collapsed, but Violet eventually married her dance partner in 1936 (on the 50-yard line at the Cotton Bowl during the Texas Centennial Exposition, no less). Daisy wed in 1941, but the marriage lasted only two weeks.   </p>
<p>After the failure of their second film, <em><a href=" https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i6W5aFdr4zQ">Chained for Life </a></em>(1950), in which they played vaudeville performers Dorothy and Vivian Hamilton, Daisy and Violet opened The Hilton Twins&#8217; Snack Bar in Miami. The venture was not a success. An attempt to cash in on the revival of <em>Freaks</em> in 1962 ended when an unscrupulous agent absconded with their money.  </p>
<p>At the end, Violet and Daisy Hilton worked in a Charlotte, North Carolina supermarket. When they didn&#8217;t show up for work one day in 1969, the police found them dead of the &quot;Hong Kong flu&quot; in the small trailer they called home. Penniless and in debt at the time of their demise, they were buried in a donated cemetery plot. </p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/07/03/the-other-hilton-sisters/">The Other Hilton Sisters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/07/03/the-other-hilton-sisters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Whistle While You Work</title>
		<link>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/06/12/whistle-while-you-work/</link>
					<comments>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/06/12/whistle-while-you-work/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lynn Peril]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2007 14:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[bootlegging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[East LA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lynn Peril]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[moonshine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Victimless crimes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[entrepreneurs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[peanuts]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>June 12, 1927Los Angeles Is there anything more quaint than a peanut wagon, its operator on life&#8217;s downward slope yet cheerfully awaiting only a word from you to scoop up a paper sack of delicious, salty goobers? This was the face that 72-year-old Victor Tartas presented to the world&#8212;-until recently. To the untrained eye, the&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/06/12/whistle-while-you-work/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Whistle While You Work</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/06/12/whistle-while-you-work/">Whistle While You Work</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p>June 12, 1927<br />Los Angeles  </p>
<p>Is there anything more quaint than a peanut wagon, its operator on life&rsquo;s downward slope yet cheerfully awaiting only a word from you to scoop up a paper sack of delicious, salty goobers? This was the face that 72-year-old Victor Tartas presented to the world&mdash;-until recently.   </p>
<p>To the untrained eye, the steady stream of customers at the peanut stand bore testimony only to the elderly Tartas&rsquo;s business acumen and pleasant personality. But Sergeant Adams of the Los Angeles Police Department detected something peculiar in the peanut vendor&rsquo;s manner:  if an approaching customer whistled once, Tartas responded with a single blast of the peanut cart&rsquo;s horn. Two whistles were met with two toots on the horn. A quick investigation revealed several pints of whiskey nestled beneath a false bottom in the wagon.   </p>
<p>Despite evidence to the contrary (twenty gallons of moonshine, a small still and a &ldquo;quantity&rdquo; of mash were found at the peanut vendor&rsquo;s home at <a title="The peanut vendor's home." target="_blank" href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&#038;hl=en&#038;q=2118+brooklyn+avenue,+los+angeles,+california&#038;sll=37.0625,-95.677068&#038;sspn=57.162571,97.03125&#038;ie=UTF8&#038;ll=34.043948,-118.19139&#038;spn=0.014793,0.023689&#038;z=15&#038;iwloc=cent&#038;om=1">2118-1/2 Brooklyn Avenue)</a>, Tartas pleaded not guilty. Jury trial was set for September 13, 1927. Bail was fixed at $1,000&#8211;which, it must be stated, wasn&rsquo;t peanuts.    </p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/06/12/whistle-while-you-work/">Whistle While You Work</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://pensive-torvalds-020d34.netlify.app/2007/06/12/whistle-while-you-work/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
