<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="https://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="https://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="https://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="https://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="https://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>camels &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<atom:link href="https://1947project.com/tag/camels/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://1947project.com/</link>
	<description>Los Angeles De-Mythified</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 20:37:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://1947project.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-1947logoSquare-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>camels &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<link>https://1947project.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>One Hump or Two</title>
		<link>https://1947project.com/2007/09/02/one-hump-or-two/</link>
					<comments>https://1947project.com/2007/09/02/one-hump-or-two/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathan Marsak]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2007 20:13:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[nathan marsak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The wacko file]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[camels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hunting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[US Camel Corps]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>&#160; September 2, 1927San Francisco&#160; May 26, 1976.&#160; On that day I was exposed to Won Ton Ton, the Dog Who Save Hollywood, an event that catapulted my nine year-old brain into a fantasy world of 1920s Los Angeles, an event that pushed the movie I&#8217;d seen the previous weekend into the back of my&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://1947project.com/2007/09/02/one-hump-or-two/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">One Hump or Two</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/09/02/one-hump-or-two/">One Hump or Two</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p>&nbsp;<img loading="lazy" width="256" height="75" border="0" src="//farm2.static.flickr.com/1067/1291362790_f983d8f638_o.gif" alt="huntplanned" title="huntplanned" /></p>
<p>September 2, 1927<br />San Francisco&nbsp;</p>
<p>May 26, 1976.&nbsp; On that day I was exposed to <em><a title="wontonton" target="_blank" href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0075436/">Won Ton Ton, the Dog Who Save Hollywood</a></em>, an event that catapulted my nine year-old brain into a fantasy world of 1920s Los Angeles, an event that pushed the movie I&rsquo;d seen the <em>previous</em> weekend into the back of my psyche.&nbsp; That previous picture still roams around and pokes its stinky, furry head out once in a great while.&nbsp; Like now.&nbsp; That cinematic masterpiece was called <a title="hawmps!" target="_blank" href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0074614/"><em>Hawmps!</em></a></p>
<p>The 127-minute F-Troop episode that is <em>Hawmps!</em> (wherein camels, or &ldquo;hawmps,&rdquo; as Slim Pickens calls them, win slim Pickens&rsquo; heart, and Jack Elam chews scenery, and look! there&rsquo;s Denver Pyle) concerns itself with the role <a title="camelcorps" target="_blank" href="https://www.drumbarracks.org/original%20website/Camel%20Corps.html">camels</a> played in opening the western territory, courtesy of the United States Army.</p>
<p>With the War Between the States, and subsequent demise of the Camel Corps, Bactrians and Arabians were set loose, and feral camels became the stuff of legend.&nbsp; Authenticated wild camel wanderings by and large ceased in the early 1900s.</p>
<p>But yesterday, September 1, a group of San Francisco financiers&mdash;A. C Mattel, Robert F. M. Duncan, William Leib and Lloyd Stevens announced their intention to hunt camels in the deserts of Arizona.&nbsp; The paper discusses briefly the history of just why there happen to be camels therein (according to local historians, a hundred camels and sixty Arabs were imported from Arabia, but the plan failed because the Arabs disliked their jobs and went home; far be it from me to doubt the local historian of 1927, but it&rsquo;s interesting to compare this account with <a title="wiki" target="_blank" href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/US_Camel_Corps">Wikipedia&rsquo;s</a>).&nbsp; &ldquo;Backers of the proposed expedition in search of survivors expect historians and scientists to be interested in the venture.&rdquo;</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" width="470" height="167" border="0" src="//farm2.static.flickr.com/1396/1291362812_5e4cc3be4a_o.gif" alt="camelcomic" title="camelcomic" /></p>
<p>Then, today, the collected adventurers were contacted by one Arturo Carillo, who, thirty-three years ago, while making a mail trip from the Harqua Hala to the Vulture mine, captured what he considered &ldquo;the last of the camels.&quot; Unable to find a buyer for the animal, he turned it loose.&nbsp; This has heartened the intrepid camel seekers, and there are many more; A. C. Mattel, of the Honolulu-Consolidated Oil Company, said he has been swamped with letters from sportsmen all along the Pacific Coast seeking the chance to join the expedition.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" width="492" height="138" border="0" src="//farm2.static.flickr.com/1430/1291362794_125e33c2be_o.gif" alt="undaunted" title="undaunted" /></p>
<p>No follow-up, unfortunately, as to the outcome of our dashing, pith-helmeted bankers&#8217; trip into the blistering wasteland (it&#8217;s also unclear as to whether they planned to merely observe, or capture the camels, but I fear their intent was just to blast the poor beasts with their Remingtons for some rec-room head-mounting).&nbsp; </p>
<p></p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/09/02/one-hump-or-two/">One Hump or Two</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://1947project.com/2007/09/02/one-hump-or-two/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
