<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>non-support &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<atom:link href="https://1947project.com/tag/non-support-2/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://1947project.com/</link>
	<description>Los Angeles De-Mythified</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2016 19:39:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://1947project.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/03/cropped-1947logoSquare-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>non-support &#8211; 1947 Project</title>
	<link>https://1947project.com/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Of weeds, critters, beards and burning</title>
		<link>https://1947project.com/2007/11/15/of-weeds-critters-beards-and-burning/</link>
					<comments>https://1947project.com/2007/11/15/of-weeds-critters-beards-and-burning/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2007 17:05:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Burning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drugs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The wacko file]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[non-support]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pets]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[world's longest beard]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>November 15, 1927Los Angeles All around town, the news is notable. Off in Owensmouth (Canoga Park to you crazy modernists), the citizens complain there are so many stray dogs in the streets, it&#8217;s worse than Constantinople. Consider the deep valley as your next exotic vacation spot. Mrs. Andria Reyes, 34, has eleven children and a&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://1947project.com/2007/11/15/of-weeds-critters-beards-and-burning/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Of weeds, critters, beards and burning</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/11/15/of-weeds-critters-beards-and-burning/">Of weeds, critters, beards and burning</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p>November 15, 1927<br />Los Angeles</p>
<p>All around town, the news is notable.</p>
<p>Off in Owensmouth (Canoga Park to you crazy modernists), the citizens complain there are so many stray dogs in the streets, it&#8217;s worse than Constantinople. Consider the deep valley as your next exotic vacation spot.</p>
<p>Mrs. Andria Reyes, 34, has eleven children and a husband who won&#8217;t work, and they all have the munchies. That&#8217;s more or less the excuse she gave Judge Westover for her small marijuana farming operation.</p>
<p>1120 East 32nd Street was burning, and Mrs. Frankie Weaver, 64, escaped unharmed. But once on the street, she realized she&#8217;d forgotten her canary Dickey. Back into the flaming second floor she charged, only to fall back, burned, inconsolable, without her little pet. They found her on the neighbors&#8217; porch, badly injured but unaware of herself, gazing mournfully into the fire, and took her to Georgia Street for treatment.</p>
<p>And in Wahperton, North Dakota, comes the passing of Hans Langseth, who had not cut his beard since July 14, 1875. It measured 17 feet when he breathed his last, and he could not only wear it round his neck like a muffler (mmm, sexy!), but traveled the world as a circus exhibition and won the 1922 world&#8217;s longest competition at the Days of &#8217;49 celebration in Sacramento. We hear these things grow posthumously, so let&#8217;s call Hans&#8217; crowning glory 17 feet, 1 inch. Huzzah!</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/11/15/of-weeds-critters-beards-and-burning/">Of weeds, critters, beards and burning</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://1947project.com/2007/11/15/of-weeds-critters-beards-and-burning/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bad dads, loud pygmies and danger on the set</title>
		<link>https://1947project.com/2007/11/08/bad-dads-loud-pygmies-and-danger-on-the-set/</link>
					<comments>https://1947project.com/2007/11/08/bad-dads-loud-pygmies-and-danger-on-the-set/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2007 17:19:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Accidents]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Downtown]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Explosion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hollywood]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Negligence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[non-support]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pygmies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[william wellman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>November 8, 1927Los Angeles Oddities around town: World class crumb-bum Joseph Peck returned from a trip to Fort Worth only to discover he was to be made an example by the City Council, seeking to alleviate the costs associated with relief payments provided to mothers whose husbands refused to support their families. Blanche Peck, 42,&#8230; <a class="more-link" href="https://1947project.com/2007/11/08/bad-dads-loud-pygmies-and-danger-on-the-set/">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Bad dads, loud pygmies and danger on the set</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/11/08/bad-dads-loud-pygmies-and-danger-on-the-set/">Bad dads, loud pygmies and danger on the set</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="body">
<div>
<p>November 8, 1927<br />Los Angeles</p>
<p>Oddities around town:</p>
<p>World class crumb-bum Joseph Peck returned from a trip to Fort Worth only to discover he was to be made an example by the City Council, seeking to alleviate the costs associated with relief payments provided to mothers whose husbands refused to support their families. Blanche Peck, 42, of 2939 West Avenue 37, has been raising five children, ages 1 to 11, without any help from Joseph since December 1925. Now she&#8217;ll be guaranteed $2 a day for a year. That&#8217;s Papa Joe&#8217;s pay for pounding on L.A.&#8217;s new rock pile. </p>
<p>In Griffith Park, camera operator <a href="http://us.imdb.com/name/nm0794391/" target="_blank">Clifford Shirpser</a> was shooting an exploding airplane for a new William Wellman picture when he stumbled over a stone and went ass over teakettle. The heavy camera went up, then brained the fallen technician. He came to after fifteen minutes. (Shirpser was likely shooting additional footage for <a href="http://us.imdb.com/title/tt0018578/" target="_blank"><em>Wings,</em></a> which had debuted in New York in August, but which did not receive its Los Angeles premiere until January 1928.)</p>
<p>And wee, noisy Ill Ill the &quot;untamed, tree-climbing pygmy&quot; barker, recently arrested in front of the Dreamland Palace at 539 South Main Street, copped a guilty plea for violating the city&#8217;s anti-ballyhoo ordinance on two occasions, and paid $100 in fines, thus avoiding a tree-free stint in the Lincoln Heights callaboose.</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/2007/11/08/bad-dads-loud-pygmies-and-danger-on-the-set/">Bad dads, loud pygmies and danger on the set</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://1947project.com/">1947 Project</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://1947project.com/2007/11/08/bad-dads-loud-pygmies-and-danger-on-the-set/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
